<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Survey Design on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/survey-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Survey Design on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 11:12:46 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/survey-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SingleWire Software</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/singlewire-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/singlewire-software/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  Migrating a legacy platform to a cloud-bases SaaS model provides unique challenges and opportunities for product growth/clarification. Surveys and interviews are powerful tools for getting context and putting the product team in the proper frame of mind. Nothing beats testing a solution in the wild. We learned a lot by running potential solutions by users and by putting it in their hands to interact with.   Background SingleWire is a leader in the emergency notification space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candorem</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  You can learn a ton while on lunch break by asking the right questions/giving the right instructions and sending it off for remote unmoderated testing. A properly orchestrated user-centered/iterative design process can provide value for many projects, including marketing websites. Although it was early in my career and the mentorship was useful, I much prefer full-blown applications to these types of eCommerce/marketing/brochure sites that Candorem is known for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextt</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:11:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  Never underestimate the value of guerrilla UX research. Instead of spending hours debating something internally, put together a survey and put it on Reddit. Use the resources and data available to you. Utilizing a well-defined analytics suite to define funnels and focus on problem points and in-depth user research to discover why people are falling off at that point can have tremendous impacts on conversion/success rates. Mark&#39;s postmortem covers a lot of what we learned and expresses similar sentiments to what I had as we closed down Nextt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>