<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/categories/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 21:25:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/categories/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing.design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 21:25:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There are an incredibly small number of people who have professional experience in both performing arts and the tech design. Applying practices, concepts, theories, and lessons from performing arts can yield some really interesting insights and experiments for the design community. Follow along at http://performing.design   I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet lately, and that&amp;rsquo;s largely due to my recent move to NYC. Madison was great, but it was time for me to find new challenges and a new home, and NYC is the natural choice given my careers in both tech and dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Case Against Industry Experience</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-case-against-industry-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 07:31:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-case-against-industry-experience/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  While having experience working in a professional setting is important, there&#39;s a danger to only hiring people with experience in your specific industry. Having a fresh set of eyes on something can be incredibly valuable/important, and helps combat bias and theory blindness. Good designers are expert learners. We expect to need to understand the nuances of a new area of expertise.   For those that haven&amp;rsquo;t been keeping track, I recently (October 2017) moved from Madison, WI to Brooklyn, NY, and the difference in the tech industry between the two cities has been really interesting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rochester Review Master Class: Revisited</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/rochester-review-master-class-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2017 19:12:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/rochester-review-master-class-revisited/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  In the early days of software, having a product that worked was good enough. Nowadays design is the differentiator. There are multiple factors to a good design: learnability, efficiency, flexibility, aesthetics. The study of human-centered design isn&#39;t new. The same concepts that Jakob Nielsen covered in the 1980s ring true today.   In 2015, I was interviewed for the Rochester Review, my alma mater&amp;rsquo;s quarterly publication for parents and alumni.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open (Love) Letter To My Next Work Partner</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 13:54:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Transparency is paramount. Make sure there are stated objectives (even if they&#39;re inaccurate), daily check-ins, and quarterly reviews. Flexibility empowers your people to do the best work they can. Have a bias against policies, rules, and meetings. Trust is your most powerful tool. Get a bunch of good people together, point them in a direction, and get out of the way.   One of the myriad benefits of having spent so much time working as a contractor is the variety of cultures, work practices, and methodologies employed by various companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do&#39;s and Don&#39;ts of Corporate Innovation</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/dos-and-donts-of-corporate-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:23:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/dos-and-donts-of-corporate-innovation/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s a ton of potential in the corporate innovation world, and as the venture market cools, the future of early stage might be corporate. Innovation teams need certain special rules and freedoms compared to the core business, especially in highly regulated industries. Culture and environment are the most important things to define and develop in these settings. Don&#39;t settle, and don&#39;t let corporate culture interfere.   As some of you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time working in the corporate innovation team of a Fortune 500 company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We&#39;re Firing a Top-Tier Product Development Firm</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/why-were-firing-a-top-tier-product-development-firm/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 14:40:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/why-were-firing-a-top-tier-product-development-firm/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Culture trumps credentials, reputation, and pretty much everything else. Don&#39;t be afraid to pull the plug on something if it isn&#39;t working. Trust your gut and stick to your guns. If you want something done right, sometimes you have to do it yourself. Just because it has a corporate name tag doesn&#39;t mean there aren&#39;t talented people.   Some of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing recently has been with what&amp;rsquo;s known as the Business Development branch of a large company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>