<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Experience on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/categories/user-experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Experience on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 10:19:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/categories/user-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Research Playbooks: What Are They and Why You Should Have One</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/research-playbooks-what-are-they-and-why-you-should-have-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/research-playbooks-what-are-they-and-why-you-should-have-one/</guid>
      <description>Depending on your context and your background, the notion (or even terminology) of a playbook may be completely foreign or completely mundane, however there&amp;rsquo;s a huge potential upside in developing a Research Playbook for your organization. This post will go into detail as to what playbooks are, why you should have one, and how to get started. There&amp;rsquo;s also a call-to-action at the end to help produce an open-source playbook to set a standard across the industry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a UX Department from scratch at a 20-year-old Big Data Company</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for 1010data&amp;rsquo;s UX Blog
These stories usually start with some sort of “when I first heard about ___”, but in this case, that goes much further back than a) the story usually goes, and b) is really practical. 1010data has been around since 2000 and has gone through tremendous growth and change as an organization since then. Recently, we’ve embarked on a new set of changes.
Document the process  There are two things I hear time and time again when telling friends, family, and colleagues about what I’m doing at 1010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Designer&#39;s Guide to GDPR</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/a-designers-guide-to-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/a-designers-guide-to-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for and edited by Prolific Interactive
Disclaimer: Nobody who contributed to this overview of GDPR or the accompanying checklist is a lawyer. This does not constitute as legal advice. This is by no means an exhaustive list. Please consult a legal professional for specific questions.
Recall the Great Privacy Update of 2018: Your inbox was flooded with emails from apps and websites you didn’t even remember having an account with, and maybe for the first time in history, privacy policies became a meme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvisation, Creativity, and Design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
I’m certainly not the first person to write about the role of improv in creative processes, its value in broadening ways of thinking, creating general good-feelings (which, interestingly, go hand-in-hand), etc. However, the majority of what’s been written so far pertains to using improv exercises in group dynamics and doesn’t address its potential as a design tool.
Part of the inspiration behind this post is my recent participation in one of Improv Everywhere’s “MP3 Experiments”, in which a massive number of strangers volunteer to interact with a recorded set of instructions in a public space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of (Daily) Technique</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-daily-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 17:15:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-daily-technique/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
As professional artists, we’re expected to practice our craft every single day. For dancers, the main way to do this is to spend time in class (for most of us, that’s every day, if not several times a day; full-time dancers are usually in class or in the studio 6–10 hours per day, 5–6 days a week). Aside from the physical exercise (which is an important element for performing artists), all of this time spent doing roughly the same thing has many benefits and side-effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Embodied Cognition</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 14:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
Underneath a lot of what we cover in performing.design is embodied cognition, a fairly recent development psychology and cognitive science. Embodied Cognition seeks to explore the relationship between how we use our bodies and how we think/what our brains do. It’s about looking at a thinking organism holistically as opposed to focusing on the brain, including the motor system, perceptual system, and the body’s interaction with the current environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Research Checklist</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:58:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  A lot more goes into designing and running your own usability tests than people typically think. Being properly prepared can be the difference between great success and catastrophic failure for your user research. Don&#39;t underestimate how much time, energy, and resource setting up a proper usability study takes.   Update 4/30/2018 This content used to be publicly available, but a more-in-depth version is now available for purchase via MelioraLabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Considerations For IoT</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/ux-considerations-for-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:53:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/ux-considerations-for-iot/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Latency and reliability can be a major issue. You should include some sort of manual control (interface or cable). Tech literacy is another concern, especially as IoT products continue to move into the home and gain mainstream adoption. Be aware of your brand experience across all communication modalities (print, mobile, physical).   Internet of Things (IoT) has been all the rage for a hot second as more and more companies try to bring their devices online and increase access (and functionality) to customers, but it&amp;rsquo;s far too easy for things to go wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Tight Iteration</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-dangers-of-tight-iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 19:31:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-dangers-of-tight-iteration/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Getting a lot of feedback quickly isn&#39;t necessarily always the best strategy - having a guiding light is helpful as well. Users react to the level of fidelity of what you show them. You might be missing something if your fidelity doesn&#39;t match the issue in the design. Good Product Design (or at least, a good discovery phase/project plan) can alleviate these issues.   Before starting a new engagement with a client, I always ask a series of questions about their company, their processes, and the project I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product vs Project Management</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/product-vs-project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 10:04:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/product-vs-project-management/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s still a fair amount of confusion between product management and project management. Lots of people do the latter well, but the former is often forgotten/forgone. Project Management is focused on execution - securing and organizing resources, planning out tasks, and keeping things on track. Velocity. How. When. Product Management is more about vision - understanding what your users are trying to achieve, having a sense of the big picture, and making sure what&#39;s being created fits expectations and needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency of &#34;Online&#34;</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 17:37:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Notification design is important, especially in the light of ubiquitous computing. Designing to allow interrupted attention is crucial. Context matters: Users are no longer in a room at a desk on a computer.   With all the talk about unplugging, disconnecting, screen time, and going &amp;ldquo;off the grid&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s clearly been a shift in the way we interact with technology and the implications it has for society (as well as possibly our mental health).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to OkCupid</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-open-letter-to-okcupid/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 17:11:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-open-letter-to-okcupid/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  OkCupid is great, but it&#39;s broken. Fixing it should be pretty easy &amp;mdash; just give a fast, simple way to stop bad members from being bad, and let the community sort it out. Empower your users and they&#39;ll empower you.   Dear OkCupid,
I love you. Well, maybe not so much love anymore. I really like you. I really like how you&amp;rsquo;ve made your services free for everyone, and how you&amp;rsquo;re helping people connect and meet others that they never would.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Flow</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-flow/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 16:38:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-flow/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Pop-ups are distracting. Design your life to have less sudden distractions and you&#39;ll be more productive and happier. Desiging user experiences that encourage flow are good.   I&amp;rsquo;ve become more and more interested in Flow recently. As a psych major, flow is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of for a long time, but I always thought of it as something that just happens, and never gave it much thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/note-taking/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 16:22:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/note-taking/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Memory is fallible, and humans tend to remember the most intense part and the ending of any experience. Finding systems that work for you is essential to productivity. Limit the number of choices a user has to (or has the opportunity to) make. Choose smart defaults and hide most options.   I have a habit when it comes to books. When I read a book, I almost always underline/take notes in the margin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Content</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2013 14:21:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-content/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Content is just as important to UX as aesthetics. Without content, your site (and all of its functionality and pretty design) is worthless. Trying to stay up to date with blog posts is hard.   I&amp;rsquo;m going to say this straight out of the gates: this blog post is kind of a cop-out. There have been a ton of changes in my life lately, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little MIA when it comes to this blog.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DITW: Stovetop</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/ditw-stovetop/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 14:21:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/ditw-stovetop/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Sometimes things we interact with in the physical world are poorly designed. Direct mapping makes a lot more sense, and should be used whenever/wherever possible. Just because people are used to a certain design/solution does not mean it&#39;s the optimal. Don&#39;t be afraid to start from scratch.   Sometimes we come across things that, until we see an alternative, we don&amp;rsquo;t realize there&amp;rsquo;s something better than the current option.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>