<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Agency on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/agency/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Agency on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/agency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why We&#39;re Firing a Top-Tier Product Development Firm</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/why-were-firing-a-top-tier-product-development-firm</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 14:40:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/why-were-firing-a-top-tier-product-development-firm</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h3&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h3&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Culture trumps credentials, reputation, and pretty much everything else.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t be afraid to pull the plug on something if it isn&amp;rsquo;t working. Trust your gut and stick to your guns.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If you want something done right, sometimes you have to do it yourself. Just because it&amp;rsquo;s a big company doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean there aren&amp;rsquo;t talented people.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the work I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing recently has been with what&amp;rsquo;s known as the Business Development branch of a large company. Basically, it&amp;rsquo;s like a handful of small startups with a Fortune 500 budget, or something I&amp;rsquo;ve come to learn is called &amp;ldquo;corporate innovation&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the benefits of working in this environment is the incredible access to resources our teams have. I&amp;rsquo;m used to the early-stage startup world, where there&amp;rsquo;s no money, no time, a million things to do, and everything is on fire, whereas the world of corporate innovation is very, very different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For one project, we decided we needed some additional help, so we decided to hire an agency to help us get an MVP up and running.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;nobody-ever-got-fired-for-buying-ibm-a-name-ibm-href-ibm-i-class-ion-link-i-a&#34;&gt;Nobody Ever Got Fired For Buying IBM &lt;a name=&#34;ibm&#34; href=&#34;#ibm&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;go-with-the-internationally-acclaimed-option&#34;&gt;Go with the internationally acclaimed option&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We interviewed about a dozen firms, including local options as well as national/international agencies, and weighed the pros and cons of working with each. Some simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t offer the bandwidth or the expertise we needed. Others we felt weren&amp;rsquo;t paying attention to our needs and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a good fit for the phase our product was in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While we said no to some extremely well-known and highly reputable companies, we ultimately went with one that had a great reputation/track record, lots of really exciting examples, and that we were excited to work with. While none of us had any experience working with this company in the past, we felt good about it. After all, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.quora.com/What-does-the-phrase-Nobody-ever-got-fired-for-choosing-IBM-mean&#34;&gt;nobody ever got fired for buying IBM&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of my role on this team was to make sure these agencies were passing the &amp;ldquo;sniff test&amp;rdquo;, and to pick one that would be the best fit for what our product (and team) needed, and I was fully confident in moving forward with this partner.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;bait-and-switch-a-name-bait-and-switch-href-bait-and-switch-i-class-ion-link-i-a&#34;&gt;Bait and Switch? &lt;a name=&#34;bait-and-switch&#34; href=&#34;#bait-and-switch&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;an-unfortunate-circumstance&#34;&gt;An unfortunate circumstance&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Things got off to a bit of a rocky start, as scheduling around the holidays is virtually impossible, but there isn&amp;rsquo;t much one can do about that. There was something that was particularly interesting about this experience, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The individuals we were talking with throughout the courtship process seemed to completely understand where we were, what we were looking for, and were on board with the rough outline I (as the in-house designer) had laid out. When asked, they reassured us that this was in fact the team we&amp;rsquo;d be working with. However, when it came to scheduling, there seemed to be a few conflicts, and after having to push back the start date, we also learned that these team members wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be available any longer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t want to take anything away from the individuals we did work with, but this kind of felt like a bait-and-switch on our end. Not only was there now a disconnect between everything we&amp;rsquo;d talked to this team about and the new team, it just didn&amp;rsquo;t quite feel right. Cue foreshadowing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;culture-mismatches-a-name-culture-href-culture-i-class-ion-link-i-a&#34;&gt;Culture Mismatches &lt;a name=&#34;culture&#34; href=&#34;#culture&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;short-work-days-every-holiday-off-laid-back-attitudes&#34;&gt;Short work days, every holiday off, laid back attitudes&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once we locked in a start date, things seemed to be moving smoothly. As is typical, we kicked off our engagement with a week-long &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gv.com/sprint/&#34;&gt;Product Design Sprint&lt;/a&gt; on-site in one of their offices. It was a great opportunity to get all of us out of our typical environment and give us an excuse to focus exclusively on this project, to (hopefully) learn something about their process, and obviously to built rapport with the team so we could work effectively going forward (especially considering it would be remote).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our half of the team was totally jazzed up to get this project moving and to hit the ground running, so despite one of the worst travel days of my life (the perfect storm of a computer glitch and a winter storm) which resulted us getting into town Monday afternoon instead of Sunday night, we were ready to put in long hours and have something we were proud to show off at the end of the week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any design sprint is going to be an intensive, exhausting experience, and I&amp;rsquo;m all for working smarter versus harder, but our initial experience wasn&amp;rsquo;t exactly what we expected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;quality-a-name-quality-href-quality-i-class-ion-link-i-a&#34;&gt;Quality &lt;a name=&#34;quality&#34; href=&#34;#quality&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;now-what-a-name-now-what-href-now-what-i-class-ion-link-i-a&#34;&gt;Now What? &lt;a name=&#34;now-what&#34; href=&#34;#now-what&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-plug&#34;&gt;A brief plug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you have similar experiences to share? Are you in a similar situation, trying to decide how to move forward with a project and who to hire? I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to talk more about it (and hopefully help you make that incredibly difficult decision). &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:me@bradorego.com&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s chat&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>