<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>User Experience on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/user-experience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in User Experience on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:19:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/user-experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a UX Department from scratch at a 20-year-old Big Data Company</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for 1010data&amp;rsquo;s UX Blog
These stories usually start with some sort of “when I first heard about ___”, but in this case, that goes much further back than a) the story usually goes, and b) is really practical. 1010data has been around since 2000 and has gone through tremendous growth and change as an organization since then. Recently, we’ve embarked on a new set of changes.
Document the process  There are two things I hear time and time again when telling friends, family, and colleagues about what I’m doing at 1010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Embodied Cognition</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 14:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
Underneath a lot of what we cover in performing.design is embodied cognition, a fairly recent development psychology and cognitive science. Embodied Cognition seeks to explore the relationship between how we use our bodies and how we think/what our brains do. It’s about looking at a thinking organism holistically as opposed to focusing on the brain, including the motor system, perceptual system, and the body’s interaction with the current environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UX Considerations For IoT</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/ux-considerations-for-iot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 May 2017 11:53:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/ux-considerations-for-iot/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Latency and reliability can be a major issue. You should include some sort of manual control (interface or cable). Tech literacy is another concern, especially as IoT products continue to move into the home and gain mainstream adoption. Be aware of your brand experience across all communication modalities (print, mobile, physical).   Internet of Things (IoT) has been all the rage for a hot second as more and more companies try to bring their devices online and increase access (and functionality) to customers, but it&amp;rsquo;s far too easy for things to go wrong.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>