<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 21:25:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing.design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 21:25:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There are an incredibly small number of people who have professional experience in both performing arts and the tech design. Applying practices, concepts, theories, and lessons from performing arts can yield some really interesting insights and experiments for the design community. Follow along at http://performing.design   I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet lately, and that&amp;rsquo;s largely due to my recent move to NYC. Madison was great, but it was time for me to find new challenges and a new home, and NYC is the natural choice given my careers in both tech and dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Designers Need to Know About Development</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 01:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s a lot of discussion around whether designers should code. Here&#39;s my take on it. Short answer: No, but you should be aware of the technology. As a designer, having at least a vague idea of how the technology behind the products you&#39;re working on is beneficial, both in terms of the design work you do and in communicating with other team members. There may be certain quirks based on implementation, but overall the pattern is Database -- Server-side -- (API) -- (Middleware) -- Front-End -- Visual/UI Design   It seems that everyone has an opinion on whether designers should code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Static</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:26:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Static generators (e.g. Hugo) are pretty cool. Ease of use/production directly relates to content creation. It&#39;s okay to borrow aesthetics/technologies/designs from others.   As you might be able to tell, my last blog post is from 2014. It was about time to get back on the blog horse but also give the site a little facelift. I&amp;rsquo;d migrated blog platforms in the past, but never really took the time to think about how my own personal site was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candorem</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</guid>
      <description>About Since Candorem’s inception in 2010, they’ve had the privilege of providing strategic marketing solutions for a wide range of organizations including American Family Insurance, Better Business Bureau of Wisconsin, Verlo Mattress, Process Retail Group, and Henry Vilas Zoo among others. Located in Lake Mills, WI (between Madison and Milwaukee), Candorem has won several awards in recent years, including a project I assisted research and design for, Transform Milwaukee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebradog</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</guid>
      <description>About Zebradog is an environmental graphic design firm located in Madison, WI who specializes in creating immersive, branded experiences for their clients. Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s multidisciplinary team of architects, graphic designers, and software developers blend the physical and digital realms, creating novel digital applications of technology for interactive multimedia and website design.
Technology Working with Zebradog gave me the opportunity to work with an extremely talented team as well as push the limits of web technology in the interactive multimedia space.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>