<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Design on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Design on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:19:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A Designer&#39;s Guide to GDPR</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/a-designers-guide-to-gdpr/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Oct 2018 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/a-designers-guide-to-gdpr/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for and edited by Prolific Interactive
Disclaimer: Nobody who contributed to this overview of GDPR or the accompanying checklist is a lawyer. This does not constitute as legal advice. This is by no means an exhaustive list. Please consult a legal professional for specific questions.
Recall the Great Privacy Update of 2018: Your inbox was flooded with emails from apps and websites you didn’t even remember having an account with, and maybe for the first time in history, privacy policies became a meme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvisation, Creativity, and Design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
I’m certainly not the first person to write about the role of improv in creative processes, its value in broadening ways of thinking, creating general good-feelings (which, interestingly, go hand-in-hand), etc. However, the majority of what’s been written so far pertains to using improv exercises in group dynamics and doesn’t address its potential as a design tool.
Part of the inspiration behind this post is my recent participation in one of Improv Everywhere’s “MP3 Experiments”, in which a massive number of strangers volunteer to interact with a recorded set of instructions in a public space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Performing.design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Apr 2018 21:25:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/performing.design/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There are an incredibly small number of people who have professional experience in both performing arts and the tech design. Applying practices, concepts, theories, and lessons from performing arts can yield some really interesting insights and experiments for the design community. Follow along at http://performing.design   I&amp;rsquo;ve been quiet lately, and that&amp;rsquo;s largely due to my recent move to NYC. Madison was great, but it was time for me to find new challenges and a new home, and NYC is the natural choice given my careers in both tech and dance.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Designers Need to Know About Development</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 01:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s a lot of discussion around whether designers should code. Here&#39;s my take on it. Short answer: No, but you should be aware of the technology. As a designer, having at least a vague idea of how the technology behind the products you&#39;re working on is beneficial, both in terms of the design work you do and in communicating with other team members. There may be certain quirks based on implementation, but overall the pattern is Database -- Server-side -- (API) -- (Middleware) -- Front-End -- Visual/UI Design   It seems that everyone has an opinion on whether designers should code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Static</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:26:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Static generators (e.g. Hugo) are pretty cool. Ease of use/production directly relates to content creation. It&#39;s okay to borrow aesthetics/technologies/designs from others.   As you might be able to tell, my last blog post is from 2014. It was about time to get back on the blog horse but also give the site a little facelift. I&amp;rsquo;d migrated blog platforms in the past, but never really took the time to think about how my own personal site was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candorem</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  You can learn a ton while on lunch break by asking the right questions/giving the right instructions and sending it off for remote unmoderated testing. A properly orchestrated user-centered/iterative design process can provide value for many projects, including marketing websites. Although it was early in my career and the mentorship was useful, I much prefer full-blown applications to these types of eCommerce/marketing/brochure sites that Candorem is known for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebradog</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  You can teach an old dog (pun intended) new tricks: teaching a 20-year-old organization how to be more agile has its challenges and benefits. Interactive multimedia (&#34;environmental graphic design&#34;) is a unique design/technology challenge, and while testing is important, it&#39;s mostly in the form of dogfooding (yes, pun also intended). Your users, in this setting, are passersby. They have no idea what you&#39;re building, and there aren&#39;t any trends to rely on, so designing for discoverability is crucial.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>