<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>bradorego.com</title>
    <link>https://bradorego.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 19:31:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bradorego.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Dangers of Tight Iteration</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/the-dangers-of-tight-iteration</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/dangers-of-tight-iteration/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2016 19:31:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/the-dangers-of-tight-iteration</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Getting a lot of feedback quickly isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily always the best strategy - having a guiding light is helpful as well.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Users react to the level of fidelity of what you show them. You might be missing something if your fidelity doesn&amp;rsquo;t match the issue in the design.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Good Product Design (or at least, a good discovery phase/project plan) can alleviate these issues.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before starting a new engagement with a client, I always ask a series of questions about their company, their processes, and the project I&amp;rsquo;ll be working on. One of those questions asks how they&amp;rsquo;re currently handling user research and product design and I&amp;rsquo;m often told they &amp;ldquo;have a tight feedback loop&amp;rdquo; and that&amp;rsquo;s all they have to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s a lot wrong with this answer, but let&amp;rsquo;s unpack it a little.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;rapid-prototyping-a-name-rapidprototyping-href-rapidprototyping-i-class-ion-link-i-a:bed2c57243224eaf92c5dc8e3d145ddb&#34;&gt;Rapid Prototyping &lt;a name=&#34;rapidPrototyping&#34; href=&#34;#rapidPrototyping&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First and foremost, effective use of Rapid Prototyping can be immensely beneficial to a product. If there&amp;rsquo;s one thing I could convince every company in the world to do, it would be to use some type of rapid prototyping in their product design. If I got a fraction of all of the &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/13549/the-10-worst-product-fails-of-all-time/&#34;&gt;money spent&lt;/a&gt; building products that ultimately failed, I&amp;rsquo;d never have to work again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately, Rapid Prototyping is more a process or practice than a technique or specific tools. Rapid Prototyping involves getting as much feedback as often as possible throughout the design process, and this is accomplished by varying the level of fidelity of what you&amp;rsquo;re testing (more on this later). By exposing the current version of your product in all of its incomplete glory, you save sinking time into things that don&amp;rsquo;t work, and ultimately build a better product for your target user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can read more about the variety of options when it comes to Rapid Prototyping elsewhere, but here&amp;rsquo;s a brief overview of some of the options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paper Prototypes - hand-drawn sketches of what an interface might look like&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wizard of Oz - the practice of playing the role of the computer by abstracting future functionality away&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing Your Competitor - before building your solution, see what problems users have with existing solutions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Interactive Prototypes - semi-functional software systems users can interact with&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;let-s-talk-about-fidelity-a-name-fidelity-href-fidelity-i-class-ion-link-i-a:bed2c57243224eaf92c5dc8e3d145ddb&#34;&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s Talk About Fidelity &lt;a name=&#34;fidelity&#34; href=&#34;#fidelity&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The exact definition of fidelity isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly clear, but it roughly refers to the level of detail your current iteration includes. It&amp;rsquo;s often used in the context of prototyping, but it can refer to existing products as well. Your typical startup MVP is a high-fidelity prototype but a low-fidelity product. Fidelity exists on a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.smashingmagazine.com/2010/06/design-better-faster-with-rapid-prototyping/#the-prototyping-spectrum&#34;&gt;continuum&lt;/a&gt;, with the lower end including concepts, sketches, and rough wireframes, and the higher end being branded/visually design and interactive prototypes. I&amp;rsquo;ve seen far too many products that jump right into the deep end of fidelity, missing out on all of the potential learning from testing lower fidelity prototypes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/dangers-of-tight-iteration/graph.jpg&#34; /&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2010/05/sketches-and-wireframes-and-prototypes-oh-my-creating-your-own-magical-wizard-experience.php&#34;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might be somewhat contradictory to recommend using a lower level of detail, but you have to &lt;a href=&#34;https://blinkux.com/blog/choosing-the-right-level-of-fidelity-for-your-wireframes/&#34;&gt;match your level of fidelity&lt;/a&gt; to the type of feedback you&amp;rsquo;re looking for. Your users will respond to the fidelity they&amp;rsquo;re given, and their feedback will be colored by this. If you give them paper, they&amp;rsquo;ll talk about things like workflow, high-level design, and desired features. If you give them highly designed (read: Sketch/Photoshop) images, they&amp;rsquo;ll talk about things like color scheme, fonts, and whitespace. If you give them an interactive prototype, they&amp;rsquo;ll talk about things like transitions, interactivity, and performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This graph (and more great coverage of the pluses and minuses of different levels of fidelity) from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.uxmatters.com/mt/archives/2010/05/sketches-and-wireframes-and-prototypes-oh-my-creating-your-own-magical-wizard-experience.php&#34;&gt;UX Matters&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;why-it-matters-a-name-why-href-why-i-class-ion-link-i-a:bed2c57243224eaf92c5dc8e3d145ddb&#34;&gt;Why It Matters &lt;a name=&#34;why&#34; href=&#34;#why&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be intoxicating to set a baseline and watch your numbers improve on whatever metrics you&amp;rsquo;ve set, as you iterate. Arguably, data-informed design is a good thing, especially compared to the alternative. The &lt;a href=&#34;http://adaptivepath.org/ideas/data-informed-not-data-driven-the-subtext/&#34;&gt;problem&lt;/a&gt; is when data starts driving your decisions, and you lose sight of the big picture - improving the experience for the end user. Increased conversions, decreased errors, or more efficient interactions may not necessarily be the most enjoyable experience (e.g. a &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.people.hbs.edu/rbuell/papers/buell_norton_2011.pdf&#34;&gt;wait time&lt;/a&gt; might actually be a &lt;em&gt;good&lt;/em&gt; thing).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem with this approach is it might be honing in on what&amp;rsquo;s known as a local maxima. Naive &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hill_climbing&#34;&gt;hill-climbing&lt;/a&gt; algorithms can fall victim to this problem as well. Essentially, you continue to see improvements and make changes until you reach a point where those improvements either diminish entirely or degrade. At this point, traditional wisdom would be to stop working and either a) work on something else, or b) declare yourself victorious and toast your achievement, all the while missing what could be a better solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/dangers-of-tight-iteration/local-maxima.jpg&#34; /&gt;
  &lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.90percentofeverything.com/2011/01/06/local-maxima-and-the-perils-of-data-driven-design/&#34;&gt;Credit&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a philosophical note, I like to think of every design problem (if not every problem in life) as something like the above graphic, except the plane is infinite &amp;ndash; there&amp;rsquo;re always other options, some of which might be better than our current situation if we&amp;rsquo;re just willing to take the leap of faith and try a new approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;fighting-the-local-maxima-a-name-local-href-local-i-class-ion-link-i-a:bed2c57243224eaf92c5dc8e3d145ddb&#34;&gt;Fighting the Local Maxima &lt;a name=&#34;local&#34; href=&#34;#local&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now we&amp;rsquo;re aware of the problem and what causes it. That doesn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily tell us what to do about it, though. Here&amp;rsquo;s a great strategy outlined in an article from 2010:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  One strategy we might employ is to optimize until we reach a point of diminishing returns: design until changes just aren’t having a big effect. Then, stop optimizing and return to other kinds of analysis to figure out the next steps. Conduct interviews. Do user testing. Give surveys, ask questions. Find out the biggest existing pain points instead of focusing on tiny design elements at this stage. Focus at the activity-level. What are people trying to accomplish? What are their higher-level goals? What aren’t people doing that we want them to? What big hurdles keep them from taking the next action? This level of insight will allow you to make those bigger changes.
  &lt;footer&gt;Joshua Porter, &lt;a href=&#34;http://52weeksofux.com/post/694598769/the-local-maximum&#34;&gt;52 Weeks of UX&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/footer&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I couldn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo;ve said it better myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-plug:bed2c57243224eaf92c5dc8e3d145ddb&#34;&gt;A brief plug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you find yourself reading this post and thinking &amp;ldquo;our products have definitely suffered from the wrong type of feedback&amp;rdquo;? Part of the reason this has come up a lot for me is I&amp;rsquo;m looking into a product-manager-as-a-service model. You should &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bradley.orego@gmail.com&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>prototype,user-centered design,fidelity,rapid iteration,product management,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Product vs Project Management</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/product-vs-project-management</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/default-bg2.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2016 10:04:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/product-vs-project-management</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s still a fair amount of confusion between product management and project management. Lots of people do the latter well, but the former is often forgotten/forgone.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Project Management is focused on execution - securing and organizing resources, planning out tasks, and keeping things on track. Velocity. How. When.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Product Management is more about vision - understanding what your users are trying to achieve, having a sense of the big picture, and making sure what&amp;rsquo;s being created fits expectations and needs. Trajectory. What. Why.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.brainmates.com.au/brainrants/project-manager-vs-product-manager&#34;&gt;hardly&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;a href=&#34;https://koombea.com/blog/the-difference-between-product-and-project-management/&#34;&gt;first&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://radar.oreilly.com/2014/02/building-the-right-thing-vs-building-the-thing-right.html&#34;&gt;person&lt;/a&gt; to write about this (though &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.fastcodesign.com/3055429/how-to-avoid-making-products-no-one-wants&#34;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt; is particularly relevant/pointed), but it&amp;rsquo;s been coming up a lot for me lately as I think about what I want to do next, work-wise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that I&amp;rsquo;ve seen come up time and time again is the need for a Product Manager. It seems that most companies have a great sense of how to execute, and they&amp;rsquo;re great at the work that they do, but figuring out what they should be doing can be a struggle. This shows up for consulting firms in the form of rework and for product firms in the form of failed product launches. I will always cringe when I think about how much time and money is wasted creating &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.buzzfeed.com/kirstenking/products-literally-no-one-asked-for?utm_term=.glwJ8aEdE#.cf5ekOv5v&#34;&gt;things people don&amp;rsquo;t want&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So let&amp;rsquo;s talk about some of these differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;project-management-a-name-project-href-project-i-class-ion-link-i-a:2bc9b53639a6b650caacc5bab7e9a353&#34;&gt;Project Management &lt;a name=&#34;proJect&#34; href=&#34;#proJect&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project&lt;/em&gt; - a (often temporary) endeavor undertaken in order to complete a task, achieve a goal, or create a product or service. Casually, a project is just a thing a person or group does to accomplish something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Project Manager&lt;/em&gt; - the individual responsible for coordinating resources, tasks, and schedule in order to ensure the project is successful. This often includes things like getting stakeholder buy in, securing a budget and/or time, assembling the right team of individuals, picking a methodology (whether agile, waterfall, or anything else), creating a backlog, planning tasks, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful Project Managers are good at getting the right people involved and following up with them to make sure they have everything they need to fulfill their role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Common Questions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who do you need for this project?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When will the project be delivered?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the current project velocity?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What can we get in scope given the budget and/or timeline restrictions?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In what order will features be implemented?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;product-management-a-name-product-href-product-i-class-ion-link-i-a:2bc9b53639a6b650caacc5bab7e9a353&#34;&gt;Product Management &lt;a name=&#34;proDuct&#34; href=&#34;#proDuct&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Product&lt;/em&gt; - a good, service, or tool built in order to solve a problem for a user (or, ideally, users). Casually, a product is something people use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Product Manager&lt;/em&gt; - the individual responsible for figuring out what the thing is supposed to do and how it&amp;rsquo;s supposed to do that. This may include determining feasibility from a business/financial standpoint, conducting any market and/or user research required to gain insights into who the end user is and what their needs are, defining a set of features to satisfy user needs, creating low-fidelity prototypes in order to communicate feature sets and behaviors, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Successful Product Managers are good at knowing what role their product serves and for whom, and ideally can align business goals with the needs of the end user.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Common Questions&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is the target user? The &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=ux+personas&#34;&gt;more specific, the better&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Who is the customer? (this is sometimes different than the user)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are their needs? Wants? Fears?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How does this product solve user needs?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What is the benefit to the end user, especially compared to their current solution?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;separate-but-equal-a-name-separate-href-separate-i-class-ion-link-i-a:2bc9b53639a6b650caacc5bab7e9a353&#34;&gt;Separate, but equal? &lt;a name=&#34;separate&#34; href=&#34;#separate&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we&amp;rsquo;ve defined some of the differences between the two PMs, we can better understand the role each fills, what their concerns are, and why they&amp;rsquo;re important to success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Product Managers are going to be talking to a lot of different stakeholders early on in the lifecycle and making sure it makes sense to move forward with a project. Product Managers are going to be doing a lot of the discovery phase of a project, and then stay involved throughout the implementation to make sure what&amp;rsquo;s being built matches the idea (as well as, ideally, running users through interim usability studies to catch any issues that were hard to predict before having an artifact to interact with).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Project Managers are going to be more involved in the day-to-day of a buildout, having little interaction with the product before that step of the process (sure, it&amp;rsquo;s possible to have a PJM involved through the process in order to have background knowledge but also keep track of resources through the entire lifecycle, but in my experience that&amp;rsquo;s the abnormal case). Project Managers will be focusing on managing expectations of the stakeholders, interfacing with the Product Manager, and securing whatever resources are needed. The Project Manager is also going to be working with the implementation team, making sure they&amp;rsquo;re on task and working well interpersonally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;
http://allaboutproductmanagement.blogspot.com/2007/03/project-manager-or-product-manager.html&#34;&gt;classic analogy&lt;/a&gt; is the project manager as a midwife, whereas the product manager is the mother. Project will come in to deliver the baby, but all of the preparation before and all of the care afterwards is up to Product. I like to think of it more like an architect versus a foreman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of the planning, research, and vision is the architect&amp;rsquo;s responsibility, and once the building is done, they&amp;rsquo;re the ones who everyone will look to when the building is successful or not (obviously there&amp;rsquo;s some back and forth with engineering as well in terms of feasibility&amp;hellip;another parallel in software). The foreman is responsible for making sure his team can execute and do what&amp;rsquo;s been planned out, but they&amp;rsquo;re often the unsung heroes of a successful project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr/&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;a-brief-plug:2bc9b53639a6b650caacc5bab7e9a353&#34;&gt;A brief plug&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Did you find yourself reading this post and thinking &amp;ldquo;we&amp;rsquo;ve got the project part down, but shoot, having a product person would be great&amp;rdquo;? Part of the reason this has come up a lot for me is I&amp;rsquo;m looking into a product-manager-as-a-service model. You should &lt;a href=&#34;mailto:bradley.orego@gmail.com&#34;&gt;contact me&lt;/a&gt; if you&amp;rsquo;d like to hear more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>user-centered design,product management,management,vision,execution,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Personal Ionic Prototypes</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/personal-ionic-prototypes</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/ionic/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 May 2016 12:30:41 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/personal-ionic-prototypes</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:11c87cc1844e7dee51d304acbe274760&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ionic Framework was &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ionic.io/announcing-ionic/&#34;&gt;first released&lt;/a&gt; in October 2013 and has since taken the hybrid app development world by storm, recently announcing their &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ionic.io/announcing-ionics-8-5m-series-a/&#34;&gt;Series A&lt;/a&gt;. I built my first full-fledged Ionic app in earnest almost a year after the platform was announced. Since then, I&amp;rsquo;ve worked with companies to build dozens of Ionic apps for everything from pure prototypes to production-level applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, here&amp;rsquo;s a short list of Ionic apps I&amp;rsquo;ve built for my own purposes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;newsflash-news-app-a-name-newsflash-href-newsflash-i-class-ion-link-i-a:11c87cc1844e7dee51d304acbe274760&#34;&gt;NewsFlash News App &lt;a name=&#34;newsflash&#34; href=&#34;#newsflash&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;NewsFlash was built using what was, at the time, a brand new feature in Ionic: swipeable cards. I&amp;rsquo;d done some work to take a demo the core team put together and enabled bi-directional swiping, and then added a little more code to allow a developer to know which direction a user swiped (the core team only offered a callback for when it was swiped) (also worth noting that both of these features are now part of the core offering).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea behind NewsFlash was that I never got around to reading any content on my RSS feeds. Even in the days of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/reader/about/&#34;&gt;Google Reader&lt;/a&gt;, my list of feeds always left me with hundreds of articles to read and no good way to sort through what was interesting. Given the recent fame of the Tinder-style swipe interaction, I had the idea to create &amp;ldquo;Tinder for RSS&amp;rdquo;. Add your feeds, swipe right to save the stories you care about, left to discard them. The app keeps track of what you&amp;rsquo;ve previously saved so you have one place to manage your reading list. See a quick demo below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/74PqgIf3uUk&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;trackme-personal-tracker-a-name-trackme-href-trackme-i-class-ion-link-i-a:11c87cc1844e7dee51d304acbe274760&#34;&gt;TrackMe Personal Tracker &lt;a name=&#34;trackme&#34; href=&#34;#trackme&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TrackMe came out of a frustration with other tracking apps as well as inspiration from Nick Felton, who&amp;rsquo;s been tracking his life in various ways and producing infographics &lt;a href=&#39;http://feltron.com/FAR05.html&#39;&gt;as far back as 2005&lt;/a&gt;. The thought is: if we have an easy way to track anything, and we store this data, we can use something like &lt;a href=&#34;https://d3js.org/&#34;&gt;D3.js&lt;/a&gt; to generate interactive infographics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;TrackMe is another example of a minimalist application - one whose design is simple and purpose is singular. Users create items to track, and then add individual entries to update the total value of whatever they&amp;rsquo;re tracking. Positive, negative, integer, whole number; mileage, reps, money spent, time spent - the application doesn&amp;rsquo;t care what you&amp;rsquo;re tracking. It&amp;rsquo;s up to you to track. Eventually, we&amp;rsquo;ll be offering a set of tools to build whatever infographics you want as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/7NZMM5rN_pA&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;better-mcbw-a-name-mcbw-href-mcbw-i-class-ion-link-i-a:11c87cc1844e7dee51d304acbe274760&#34;&gt;Better MCBW &lt;a name=&#34;mcbw&#34; href=&#34;#mcbw&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Better MCBW has its own entire post explaining the motivation and process. You can read more about it &lt;a href=&#34;https://bradorego.com/2016-05-better-mcbw/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. Better MCBW has seen a decent amount of traction among Madison Craft Beer Week participants despite the entire motivation being my own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yAJx1i41d04&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <tags>ionic,ionic framework,firebase,product development,prototype,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better MCBW</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/better-mcbw</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/better-mcbw/header.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 May 2016 18:29:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/better-mcbw</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://ionicframework.com&#34;&gt;Ionic&lt;/a&gt; lets you build apps ridiculously fast. Write once, build many.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t like how something&amp;rsquo;s done, instead of just complaining about it, do something to make it better.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reverse engineering is easier than ever. Your success is not a factor of your codebase, but about the value you offer an end-user.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The end result: &lt;a href=&#34;http://mcbw.herokuapp.com&#34;&gt;Better MCBW&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;backstory-a-name-backstory-href-backstory-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Backstory &lt;a name=&#34;backstory&#34; href=&#34;#backstory&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://madbeerweek.com&#34;&gt;Madison Craft Beer Week&lt;/a&gt; has been one of my favorite events since moving to Madison. Started as a grassroots project by a few local beer lovers, the event has ballooned to one of the best in the nation, featuring over 550 events this year. In years past, I&amp;rsquo;ve been involved in helping out on the tech side of things, and we had big plans for this upcoming year. But in September 2015, The Isthmus &lt;a href=&#34;http://isthmus.com/food-drink/beer/isthmus-acquires-madison-craft-beer-week/&#34;&gt;acquired Craft Beer Week&lt;/a&gt;, and took over all operations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After hearing that the 2016 was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.facebook.com/MadBeerWeek/posts/1225581240785685&#34;&gt;built natively&lt;/a&gt;, and as an Android user I would have to wait to get my hands on it, questions arose as to why such a technically/mechanically simple app wasn&amp;rsquo;t built using &lt;a href=&#34;http://ionicframework.com&#34;&gt;Ionic&lt;/a&gt;, a mobile app development framework built by a company based in Madison. After I got my hands on the Android app itself, I was less than enthusiastic about its performance and feature set.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;reverse-engineering-it-a-name-reverse-href-reverse-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Reverse Engineering It &lt;a name=&#34;reverse&#34; href=&#34;#reverse&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, realizing that my complaints weren&amp;rsquo;t getting anyone anywhere (not to mention I lacked the necessary context to know why they made the decisions they made), I had an idea: I have the APK, so I can decompile it, dig through it, and figure out exactly what API calls they&amp;rsquo;re making, and then emulate them with my own codebase. Simple enough, right? Well, for someone that knows virtually nothing about native Android development, this task proved simple yet pointless. I only gained one insight from it, which was the URL of their API. Then another idea hit me: why not just set up a proxy and read the HTTP requests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enter-mitmproxy:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Enter &lt;code&gt;mitmproxy&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After doing a little bit of googling, I came across this &lt;a href=&#34;https://medium.com/@rotxed/how-to-debug-http-s-traffic-on-android-7fbe5d2a34#.mhbido9ys&#34;&gt;incredibly helpful article&lt;/a&gt; explaining step-by-step exactly what I wanted to do. Next thing I know, I had a proxy running on my laptop, my phone&amp;rsquo;s internet traffic streaming through that proxy, and I had access to every HTTP request the phone (and thus, the app) made. It was almost too easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/better-mcbw/mitmproxy.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-horror:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;The Horror&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, now that I had all of the HTTP requests (all, uh, 4 of them that the app seemed to be making), all I had to do was make those same requests with the same body, parse the response, and I was off to the races, right? This is all true, but in my inspection of the traffic, I came across a few horrifying realizations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every request made was a &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;. Getting the list of events? &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;. Creating an account? &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;. Logging in, and creating a session? &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;. Getting a list of special offers? &lt;code&gt;POST&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every response had a status of &lt;code&gt;200 - OK&lt;/code&gt;. If there was an error, you have to parse the body of the message. And those bodies are in no way consistent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The list of events (~580 json objects) came out to a staggering 700KB of data. Not the end of the world in today&amp;rsquo;s day and age, but a tough pill to swallow. There&amp;rsquo;s gotta be something we can do about that, right? (Spoiler alert: there is).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interacting with this API was painful. I was literally parsing a tilde(~) delimited string to determine the result of actions, and then picking parts of that out to save (e.g. the access token). This kind of feels like somebody&amp;rsquo;s first attempt at making an API.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;off-to-the-races:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Off to the Races&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All of that aside, I thought I was in the clear. Build an Ionic app, replicate the responses, do some other stuff with the data. Simple enough, right? Aaaaand then I got &lt;code&gt;CORS&lt;/code&gt;&amp;rsquo;d, which I should&amp;rsquo;ve seen coming. After trying to find a way to get Angular to work around pre-flighting requests, I decided to bite the bullet and build a node proxy. ~100 lines of &lt;code&gt;Node.js&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;Express&lt;/code&gt; code later, I was in business. Now we can send our requests to our own server which would make the same requests to the Craft Beer Week API and pass the results back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;app.post(&#39;*&#39;, function (req, res, next) {
  console.log(&amp;quot;requesting &amp;quot; + API_URL + req.originalUrl);
  request.post(API_URL + req.originalUrl, {form: req.body},
    function (error, response, body) {
      if (body.indexOf(&#39;Your session&#39;) !== -1) {
        res.status(401);
        return res.send(body);
      }
      console.log(response.statusCode + &amp;quot; - &amp;quot; + response.statusMessage);
      res.status(response.statusCode);
      res.send(body);
    });
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;feature-parity:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Feature Parity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all of that behind us, all we needed was to do was create the Ionic app to do what the native app did. Considering the native app is just a list of events, that was pretty straightforward. As part of this process, I&amp;rsquo;d spun up a little &lt;a href=&#34;http://firebase.com&#34;&gt;Firebase database&lt;/a&gt; to save my own version of user accounts (which I was still creating via the MCBW API). Further inspection of the app&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;save&amp;rdquo; feature revealed a lack of persistence of those events (it was only saving it on the device), so in trying to replicate features I was actually already improving the experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest, as they say, is history (or, at least, trivial).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;deploying-to-heroku:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Deploying to Heroku&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having a feature-parity Ionic app on your local machine is great and all, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t do much good. Enter &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.ionic.io/heroku-ionic/&#34;&gt;Ionic Heroku&lt;/a&gt;, which is a nifty little boilerplate that takes care of all of the setup and deploy configuration Heroku needs. You can hit one button, punch in a name, and you have a Heroku app. Copy your www/ file into the boilerplate&amp;rsquo;s (and update any npm/bower/ionic config you need to) and you&amp;rsquo;re golden. This was possibly the easiest step in the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;making-it-better-a-name-improve-href-improve-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Making It Better &lt;a name=&#34;improve&#34; href=&#34;#improve&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point, I&amp;rsquo;d spent about 8 hours including all development time and research into how their API worked. I could&amp;rsquo;ve called it a day - I&amp;rsquo;d built an app that reached feature parity and could be deployed to Android and iOS. My work here was done. But, even by reaching parity, I hadn&amp;rsquo;t made anything better. At the end of the day, I was building this app for myself, so stopping here wouldn&amp;rsquo;t&amp;rsquo;ve helped. So, I set out with a short list of ways to improve the experience:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;700KB of JSON seemed like a bit much&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Date dividers would make scanning the list a lot easier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Saving a list of events is one thing, being able to share that list is another&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Different ways of sorting (e.g. by location name, by event name)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A map view would be clutch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What if I got an email every morning with my saved events for the day?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gzip-is-your-friend:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt; is your friend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do we start? What&amp;rsquo;re the low-hanging fruit? Let&amp;rsquo;s see what we can do about this JSON dump. As it turns out, the MCBW API wasn&amp;rsquo;t using any compression. Enabling &lt;code&gt;gzip&lt;/code&gt; on my Node server brought that 700 down to ~100, which is a huge improvement. Inspecting the data further, it seemed that all the data was there twice - as both an index and a keyed index. That lead to a horrific piece of code that looked something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;  delete jsonBody[i][0];
  delete jsonBody[i][1];
  delete jsonBody[i][2];
  delete jsonBody[i][3];
  delete jsonBody[i][4];
  delete jsonBody[i][5];
  delete jsonBody[i][6];
  delete jsonBody[i][7];
  delete jsonBody[i][8];
  delete jsonBody[i][9];
  delete jsonBody[i][10];
  delete jsonBody[i][11];
  delete jsonBody[i][12];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which brought us down to 80KB. Still not great, but much better than 700KB. Okay, great, what&amp;rsquo;s next? Sharing seems like it&amp;rsquo;s pretty straightforward.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;enabling-sharing:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Enabling sharing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t going to be a lecture about how powerful social sharing plugins are in viral/organic growth. I&amp;rsquo;m less concerned about that and more concerned about the end-user experience. Considering I already had my own Firebase database, enabling this was actually trivial. Create a route outside the context of the app (otherwise users would get redirected to login) that took in the user&amp;rsquo;s ID (from the URL) and pulled out the list of their saved events. Simple, straightforward, elegant. Add in a few social share buttons for convenience and the app practically markets itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/better-mcbw/sharing.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dividers:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Dividers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of the content, a 500-item list is overwhelming. Adding date dividers at least makes it a little easier to scan through. The implementation of this is actually pretty straightforward. Here&amp;rsquo;s that snippet (for dates) in all its glory:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;  for (i = 0; i &amp;lt; events.length; i++) {
    if (events[i].type !== &amp;quot;divider&amp;quot;) { /// don&#39;t process dividers if we come across them
      tempDate = new Date(events[i].start_date);
      if (currentDate.getDate() !== tempDate.getDate()) { /// tempDate is a new date!
        currentDate = tempDate;
        events.splice(i, 0, {type: &amp;quot;divider&amp;quot;, value: dayDividerFormat(currentDate)});
        i--; /// backtrack so we don&#39;t miss something
      }
    }
  }
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Couple this with &lt;code&gt;$ionInfiniteScroll&lt;/code&gt; and we have lazy-loading events 20 at a time plus dividers. Much better than spitting out a list of 500 events and having users fend for themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;searching-sorting-maps:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Searching, Sorting, Maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/better-mcbw/map.png&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s great and all, but what if I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a specific event? What if I&amp;rsquo;m in a particular part of town and I want to know what my other options are nearby? Sorting and Filtering were actually somewhat of a happy accident between what Angular offers and how I&amp;rsquo;d structured the rest of the app. When the user logs in, I fetch the list of events once and cache it. From there, pretty much everything they see is some permutation of that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount of heavy-lifting on the client, but it also means I have all the source material and we&amp;rsquo;re minimizing the number of round-trips. I already have a mechanism for adding dividers, so if I want to enable other sorting (the Node server sorts by start date by default), all I needed to do was a simple Javascript &lt;code&gt;Array.sort()&lt;/code&gt; and then pass that into the divider function.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Searching proved a little more complicated. Aforementioned lazy loading meant I couldn&amp;rsquo;t just use an Angular &lt;code&gt;$filter&lt;/code&gt; (without additional complications - I&amp;rsquo;m sure I could&amp;rsquo;ve), but that local cache made it fairly trivial. Here, &lt;code&gt;Array.filter()&lt;/code&gt; came to the rescue. A simple string compare (via the ever-popular &lt;code&gt;String.indexOf()&lt;/code&gt;) spat out the results we crave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mapping proved a little more difficult. After wrestling with all of the available Angular Google Maps solutions, I settled on &lt;a href=&#34;https://ngmap.github.io/&#34;&gt;ngMap&lt;/a&gt;. It made the most sense to me from a structural standpoint, and made a lot of the subsequent code incredibly easy to write (think: virtually no controller code to place markers and pop up and info window on click). A little date finagling to make sure we&amp;rsquo;re showing the right pins, and a tiny insight into managing 500 events on a map (which is actually something I learned from last year&amp;rsquo;s MCBW website) and we&amp;rsquo;ve finally reached a point where I think I can say I&amp;rsquo;m done. Well, almost&amp;hellip;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;checkin-da-emails:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Checkin&amp;rsquo; da Emails&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a terrible example of staying lean (as opposed to most of the other development on this project, which was driven by me trying to use my own app out in the wild), but I had the idea of sending an email every morning with the list of events you&amp;rsquo;d saved for that day. Partly because, theoretically, that eliminates the need to ever check your to-do list again. Log on once, save the events you want, and then it&amp;rsquo;ll email you your schedule for the day. Sounds ideal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After wrestling with MailGun for awhile, &lt;a href=&#34;https://sendgrid.com/&#34;&gt;SendGrid&lt;/a&gt; won out in terms of simplicity. I had test emails out within minutes, and all I had to do then was write a little server code to compile the list, do some basic HTML formatting, and that&amp;rsquo;s one more feature to add to the list. I thought I was just doing this for myself, but I was instantly validated by this exchange:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/better-mcbw/lauren.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-fuuuuuuuuuture-a-name-future-href-future-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;The Fuuuuuuuuuture &lt;a name=&#34;future&#34; href=&#34;#future&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than once already this week, people have brought up the idea of some sort of optimization algorithm. Each event has a start time, and end time, and a location. This sounds like some sort of modified Travelling Salesman Problem, and while that would be a lot of fun to try to implement, I think that&amp;rsquo;s a &amp;ldquo;next-year&amp;rdquo; type of feature. After all, I&amp;rsquo;ve already sunk a whopping ~20 hours into this project. I can only imagine what The Isthmus paid their developers and how much time they spent on this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The code could also use a serious refactor, especially on the client side. This is what happens when innovation/speed of development matters more than code quality/longevity/cost of support. Whoops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There also could be increased security, as right now I&amp;rsquo;m pretty sure if you have someone&amp;rsquo;s user ID you can modify their list of saved events, but again, 20 hours of free work plus it&amp;rsquo;s an app that&amp;rsquo;s only useful for one week (and for a beer event, no less).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;lessons-learned-a-name-lessons-href-lessons-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Lessons Learned &lt;a name=&#34;lessons&#34; href=&#34;#lessons&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;firebase-synchronized-arrays:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Firebase Synchronized Arrays&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I learned in trying to build this Saved Event feature is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.firebase.com/docs/web/libraries/angular/guide/synchronized-arrays.html&#34;&gt;Firebase arrays&lt;/a&gt; don&amp;rsquo;t work the way you think they do. I had a list of events  (JSON objects) that I would push to an array (via &lt;code&gt;$firebaseArray.$add&lt;/code&gt;), and when someone unchecked the magic box, I tried to use &lt;code&gt;$firebaseArray.$remove&lt;/code&gt;, except that only works if you&amp;rsquo;re talking about the same reference you used to push to the array. So, if you have a list of items, you push &lt;em&gt;a copy&lt;/em&gt; of one to the array, then try to remove it, it didn&amp;rsquo;t work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;keyed-arrays-make-sense-sometimes:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Keyed Arrays Make Sense Sometimes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a corollary to the above realization, keyed arrays actually make a lot of sense sometimes. The solution to this problem (while not the most elegant/efficient solution) is to create a keyed array of saved events. Every time a user saves/unsaves an event, we update the user&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;saved&lt;/code&gt; array by updating the object at that key, e.g.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;  profile.saved[event.id] = event;
  /// or
  delete profile.saved[event.id];
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;videos-a-name-videos-href-videos-i-class-ion-link-i-a:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Videos &lt;a name=&#34;videos&#34; href=&#34;#videos&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;official-mcbw:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Official MCBW:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/s4OAGhlFpcQ&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;better-mcbw:608891990651e25035713577174171c1&#34;&gt;Better MCBW:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/yAJx1i41d04&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <tags>ionic,madbeerweek,reverse engineer,ux,feature parity,firebase,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Static</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/back-to-static</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/back-to-static/header.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:26:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/back-to-static</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Static generators (e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;) are pretty cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Ease of use/production directly relates to content creation.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s okay to borrow aesthetics/technologies/designs from others.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you might be able to tell, my last blog post is from 2014. It was about time to get back on the blog horse but also give the site a little facelift. I&amp;rsquo;d &lt;a href=&#34;http://beerbatterbreakfast.com/2014/07/fancy-new-blog.html&#34;&gt;migrated blog platforms&lt;/a&gt; in the past, but never really took the time to think about how my own personal site was hosted. So let&amp;rsquo;s take a quick trip down memory lane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;static-site-2011-a-name-2011-href-2011-i-class-ion-link-i-a:713252246435f0d8330ff0c53c578039&#34;&gt;Static Site (2011) &lt;a name=&#34;2011&#34; href=&#34;#2011&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first got into web development (professionally), I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be cool to build my own website from scratch to prove my mettle. That was 2011; certainly not far enough ago by any means for most of the technologies in use today to not exist. But, I was young and naive, and had some big ideas (e.g. a live CSS switcher, replicating the exact same look/behavior with and without Javascript, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I learned very quickly from that experience that keeping a static site up to date was really difficult. Any time you made a change one place, you had to make sure you made it everywhere. You had to make sure to manage collisions. You had to handle your own deploys and routing. It was a hassle, and I virtually never updated the site, so after spending some time working with &lt;a href=&#34;https://zebradog.com&#34;&gt;ZebraDog&lt;/a&gt; and seeing the power of Drupal, I decided it was time for a change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;drupal-7-0-2012-a-name-2012-href-2012-i-class-ion-link-i-a:713252246435f0d8330ff0c53c578039&#34;&gt;Drupal 7.0 (2012) &lt;a name=&#34;2012&#34; href=&#34;#2012&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I set out to &lt;a href=&#34;https://bradorego.com/2012-11-new-site/&#34;&gt;update and re-design&lt;/a&gt; the website again, this time using something a little more powerful and modern, and to make it easier for me to create new content while still having full control and flexibility over how it&amp;rsquo;s displayed and what functionality the website had.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After all, at ZD we&amp;rsquo;d built a lot of things on Drupal, ranging from fairly simple &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kellerrealestategroup.com/&#34;&gt;real estate websites&lt;/a&gt; to fairly complicated &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mstc.edu/&#34;&gt;institutional websites&lt;/a&gt; to the backbone of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=VuicjhSpbV8&#34;&gt;interactive multimedia installations&lt;/a&gt;. I could use it to build a measly blog and portfolio website, right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The problem wasn&amp;rsquo;t whether I could; in fact the problem was probably &lt;strong&gt;that&lt;/strong&gt; I could. I built an incredible media delivery site that was isolated from the world and almost too powerful for its own good. Developing and maintaining the site was nontrivial, and adding new content, while certainly easier than a static site, was beyond me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;back-to-static-2016-a-name-2016-href-2016-i-class-ion-link-i-a:713252246435f0d8330ff0c53c578039&#34;&gt;Back to Static (2016) &lt;a name=&#34;2016&#34; href=&#34;#2016&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blog technology philosophy has shifted lately. WordPress is still the clear winner in the space, but there&amp;rsquo;s an alternative to generating the site every time it&amp;rsquo;s requested. These take the form of static generators, and make a lot more sense to me personally. Jekyll, Ghost, Hugo, Hexo; the list goes on. What&amp;rsquo;s under the hood doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter (which, as an aside, makes switching way easier) &amp;mdash; all that matters is the static HTML/CSS/JS they output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems a little weird to be going back to a static option, but there are some major differences:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have so much less to worry about in terms of upkeep and deploy thanks to things like partials and services like &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.aerobatic.com/&#34;&gt;Aerobatic&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content creation is way easier because I literally create a file and start typing. Markdown gets translated into HTML and all of the formatting and styling is handled by the templates I define.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I stand on the shoulders of giants &amp;mdash; there have been tons of people putting in tons of work to make things like this easier. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason to reinvent the wheel.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So (and I&amp;rsquo;ve said this before), theoretically keeping the site updated will be a lot easier. I somewhat feel like a cop-out for using a fairly standard template/look-and-feel, but at the end of the day, my job as a designer isn&amp;rsquo;t to make things look pretty or to be unique. My job is to provide the best experience possible for my users. In the context of a blog, that means engaging, useful content; not pretty pictures.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>meta,design,hugo,blog,drupal,content,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MobileIgniter</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/mobileigniter</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/header.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 15:11:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/mobileigniter</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:19aee21804f9101f4647ec2b7a0a8d5a&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://mobileigniter.com&#34;&gt;MobileIgniter&lt;/a&gt; is an Internet-of-Things consultancy and product development firm that has worked with numerous clients, ranging from Fortune 500 companies to early-stage startups, and touched many industries including consumer appliances, insurance, and air quality. MI&amp;rsquo;s engagements included helping companies figure out if IoT was right for their business/product from a strategic standpoint, helping ideate and prototype different interactions and feature sets having a &amp;ldquo;smart&amp;rdquo; device would afford, and as far as taking products to market. MobileIgniter has a unique combination of electrical engieering, software development, and business analysis that enables the company to contribute at every stop of the product development lifecycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with any startup/small company, individuals wear many hats and are responsible for many different roles. At MobileIgniter, I was primarily responsible for design and research, with additional support in front-end development and project management. Essentially, anything that happened between signing the contract and the app reaching production was in my wheelhouse. In particular, MI ran several marketing experiments while exploring different product opportunities, and designing the marketing material, email campaigns, and advertising campaigns was my responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately most of the work MobileIgniter has done is under NDA, so while I can&amp;rsquo;t speak publicly about specific projects, some highlights include designing and running usability studies for a Fortune 1000 company, helping a Fortune 500 company learn Angular and Agile methodologies, publishing the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/mi-tim/usability-research-checklist-58988252/mi-tim/usability-research-checklist-58988252&#34;&gt;Usability Research Checklist&lt;/a&gt;, and developing &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/MobileIgniter/ng-photon&#34;&gt;ngPhoton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-images:19aee21804f9101f4647ec2b7a0a8d5a&#34;&gt;Selected Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MobileIgniter&amp;rsquo;s IoT Landing Page
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/iot-desktop.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;LaundryMate Laundry Sensor Landing Page (Homeowner)
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/laundrymate-personal-desktop.png&#34; /&gt;
LaundryMate Buy Page
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/laundrymate-buy-mobile.png&#34; /&gt;
LaundryMate Laundry Sensor Landing Page (Laundromat User)
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/laundrymate-laundromat-desktop.png&#34; /&gt;
UXLab @ MobileIgniter Landing Page
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/mobile-igniter/uxlab-small-desktop.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>startup,entrepreneurship,ux,usability research,mobile app,ionic,iot,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency of &#34;Online&#34;</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/transparency-of-online/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 17:37:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Notification design is important, especially in the light of ubiquitous computing.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Designing to allow interrupted attention is crucial.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Context matters: Users are no longer in a room at a desk on a computer.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all the talk about unplugging, disconnecting, screen time, and going &amp;ldquo;off the grid&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s clearly been a shift in the way we interact with technology and the implications it has for society (as well as possibly our mental health). The &lt;a href=&#34;http://nationaldayofunplugging.com/&#34;&gt;National Day of Unplugging&lt;/a&gt; is dedicated to people spending ~24 hours (sundown to sundown) without engaging with technology under the premise of doing things like being more present, destressing, etc. While I could go on about how something meant to help us has become this burden of sorts, I&amp;rsquo;m more interested in the implications (from an experiential standpoint) of being forever-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;always-connected-a-name-always-href-always-i-class-ion-link-i-a:0630faa271b6c4fe5b485a19f90d0aad&#34;&gt;Always Connected &lt;a name=&#34;always&#34; href=&#34;#always&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I first noticed this subtle shift when talking to someone a few weeks ago on &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hipchat.com/&#34;&gt;HipChat&lt;/a&gt;. I was in the middle of a conversation on my laptop and knew I had to step away from the computer for a few minutes, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel any need to notify my conversation partner about this. Two main reasons - 1) if it were actually all that important/crucial, I could always answer it on my phone, and 2) the message wasn&amp;rsquo;t going anywhere so if I got back to him immediately or within the next 5-10 minutes, it didn&amp;rsquo;t really make a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed an almost identical interaction pattern with Facebook Messenger. I no longer worry whether or not the person is there, nor do I feel the need to alert others of my status. In fact, most of my conversations via FB happen over the course of hours, days, even weeks at a time. The transparency of status is completely irrelevant to our interaction because we both know the messages will be there if and when the other party gets around to responding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;it-gets-better-or-worse-a-name-better-href-better-i-class-ion-link-i-a:0630faa271b6c4fe5b485a19f90d0aad&#34;&gt;It gets better (or worse..?) &lt;a name=&#34;better&#34; href=&#34;#better&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are drawbacks to this. Everybody knows the dread associatied with the assumption that, because you have a smartphone/phone/computer/laptop/tablet/smartwatch/whatever, that you can be reached any day, any time, and that creates this obsessive need to have notifications turned on for everything. The problem gets worse as we move into more-ubiquitous forms of computing, such as wearable technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This past weekend at &lt;a href=&#34;http://madisonpl.us/ux&#34;&gt;Madison+UX&lt;/a&gt;, Philip Likens gave a talk about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/philiplikens/philip-likens-madisonux&#34;&gt;wearable computing&lt;/a&gt;, mentioning that he&amp;rsquo;s abandoned most of his wearables due to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/search?q=notifiaction+overload&amp;amp;oq=notifiaction+overload&amp;amp;aqs=chrome..69i57.2313j0j1&amp;amp;sourceid=chrome&amp;amp;es_sm=91&amp;amp;ie=UTF-8#q=notification+overload&amp;amp;spell=1&#34;&gt;notification overload&lt;/a&gt;. In (roughly) his own words, having his phone, his watch, and his Google Glass all vibrate simultaneously any time anything happened became a little overwhelming. So now, instead of having some sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going on, he doesn&amp;rsquo;t even carry his phone on his person - totally shut off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m inadventently running the same experiment - I put my phone on silent for the conference (due to the exorbitant amount of Twitter notifications I was getting) and I simply forgot to put it back on vibrate for the first day or two. What I realized is that I spent less time on minor distractions (increasing my overall &lt;a href=&#34;https://bradorego.com/2013-03-the-importance-of-flow/&#34;&gt;flow&lt;/a&gt;), and I only checked the phone when I wanted to. It was back to on-demand instead of being always on, and it&amp;rsquo;s really refreshing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;designing-notifications-a-name-notifications-href-notifications-i-class-ion-link-i-a:0630faa271b6c4fe5b485a19f90d0aad&#34;&gt;Designing Notifications &lt;a name=&#34;notifications&#34; href=&#34;#notifications&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what does this mean to us as Experience Designers? A few things:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be mindful of the perceived status for your users. Do they know their status? Does your service need a smartphone app? A watch app? Do they all need to sync between each other? What about notifications? What&amp;rsquo;s important enough to potentially disrupt someone&amp;rsquo;s train of thought?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given all of that, understand the context your users will be in. If you&amp;rsquo;re allowing them to do all of these different things in all of these different ways, how does the context of their interaction change if it&amp;rsquo;s on a computer versus a phone versus a watch?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is your interaction temporally bound? Can they pop in and out multiple times over the course of a day, a week, a month? Does it have to happen now?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What&amp;rsquo;re the implications of your product/service as wearable computers become more ubiquitous? What types of notifications can you design? &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.slideshare.net/eadahl/ux-axioms-26-principle-to-drive-better-product-design/46&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Apply Laban Movement Analysis to technology&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And of course many more.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>offline,transparency,notifications,flow,ubiquitous computing,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Clean Clear Waters</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/clean-clear-waters</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/clean-clear-waters/wires.png</image>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 15:10:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/clean-clear-waters</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:0b1dfc567fa55bcbc48ecf5d01bfe807&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the many projects I&amp;rsquo;ve been involed with via &lt;a href=&#34;http://100state.com&#34;&gt;100state&lt;/a&gt; was one in collaboration with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://cleanlakesalliance.com/&#34;&gt;Clean Lakes Alliance&lt;/a&gt;, a non-profit &amp;ldquo;dedicated to the improvement and protection of the lakes, streams, and wetlands of the Yahara Watershed&amp;rdquo;. One of their initiatives involves soliciting volunteers to collect data about water quality nearby their homes and places of work in order to monitor and gain insight on the water.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously, data collection has happened in a variety of means, such as email or a Google Spreadsheet. The first step of the project was to digitize the entire process by creating a web app that volunteers can use to log into and track their data. The second phase would be to roll out a public-facing web and mobile application that Madison beachgoers can use to check which beaches were open or closed, what the relative water quality at each location is, and to be able to submit their own visual observations of the water quality based on a few scales CLA put forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My responsibilities for this project were to take care of product design (UX, visual) as well as implement a prototype for the front-end. Josh and Jordan from &lt;a href=&#34;https://miosoft.com&#34;&gt;MIOsoft&lt;/a&gt; graciously offered to handle all of the back-end data handling and implementation. For the front-end, we chose to work with the &lt;a href=&#34;http://ionicframework.com&#34;&gt;Ionic Framework&lt;/a&gt;, deciding to go completely mobile-first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I ended my engagement on the project, MIOsoft completely took over responsibility for the project. The live version can be seen at &lt;a href=&#34;http://lakeforecast.org/&#34;&gt;Lakeforecast.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-images:0b1dfc567fa55bcbc48ecf5d01bfe807&#34;&gt;Selected Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/clean-clear-waters/wires.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/clean-clear-waters/mockup.png&#34; /&gt;
Lakeforecast.org Map View
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/clean-clear-waters/map.png&#34; /&gt;
Lakeforecast.org Beach View
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/clean-clear-waters/beach.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>clean lakes alliance,100state,ionic,product design,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextt</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/nextt</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/nextt/screens.png</image>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:11:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/nextt</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:ebeef24fe61de8fef2a98739c1cee8ca&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nextt is a social event planning tool designed to help get all of your friends on the same page and to get together offline in the real world. While working with Nextt, I was responsible for development of the mobile web app (which eventually became Nextt&amp;rsquo;s Android app), as well as overseeing parts of the overall User Experience and wrangling all of the data, metrics, and analytics to help guide product development. The most interesting and valuable piece of this experience was building everything from the ground up by hand - no frameworks, no tools. I learned a ton about mobile performance, and what it takes to develop a compelling experience on mobile.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along with advising visual design, branding, and interaction design, there were several small victories we achieved, such as increasing the unauth (invite) conversion rate from ~10% to ~40%, and streamlining the onboarding process to get users up to speed and interacting with the system in a meaningful way. I championed tight iteration loops and data-driven decisions about design and feature prioritization, and also managed all of Nextt&amp;rsquo;s usability studies, email questionnaires, and analytics suite. We prepared daily reports to the CEO and weekly to the Board to monitor our progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-images:ebeef24fe61de8fef2a98739c1cee8ca&#34;&gt;Selected Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/nextt/unauth.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/nextt/onboarding.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/nextt/screens.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>startup,entrepreneurship,ux,usability research,analytics,mobile app,mixpanel,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Enhancement with Phonegap</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/progressive-enhancement-with-phonegap</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/prog-enh-phonegap/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 16:46:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/progressive-enhancement-with-phonegap</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Enabling native-level functionality on a hosted web app is really cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Code reuse is also pretty cool.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Beware of the gotchas. There are always gotchas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: This blog post is the long-form answer to &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/20574938/progressive-enhancement-with-phonegap&#34;&gt;this StackOverflow post&lt;/a&gt; I made about it (which is, at the time of writing, the #1 Google result for &amp;ldquo;progressive enhancement phonegap&amp;rdquo;). Also worth noting this guide only addresses Android right now. Doing so for iOS should follow the same methodology though.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Github repo for this project can be found &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/borego/progressive_enhancement_phonegap&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. You can download the app (for Android) &lt;a href=&#34;http://old.bradorego.com/sites/default/files/progenhpg/prog-enh-pg.apk&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re thinking about building a web app versus a native app, I&amp;rsquo;m here to tell you that the answer is almost definitely go for a web app. Web performance (especially on mobile devices) has come a long way in the past year or so, and using tools like &lt;a href=&#34;http://phonegap.com&#34;&gt;Phonegap&lt;/a&gt;, you can get the best of both worlds (something in the app store, code reuse, platform agnosticism, leveraging web technologies). Based on some recent work/research I&amp;rsquo;ve done, it&amp;rsquo;s actually much more powerful than they&amp;rsquo;re selling it for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This post will go into detail of how to make it work, but at a very high level, all you have to do is alter the User Agent coming out of your Phonegapped app, then sniff for that special UA string on the server side of wherever your web code is living, and if it&amp;rsquo;s there, enable Phonegap-specific code. If not, let it function as a normal web app - no harm, no foul. It&amp;rsquo;s an incredibly powerful tool that lets you use ~98% of the same code for your Android/iPhone app and your web app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-0-set-up-your-phonegap-project-server-etc-a-name-setup-href-setup-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 0) Set up your Phonegap project, server, etc. &lt;a name=&#34;setup&#34; href=&#34;#setup&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This guide won&amp;rsquo;t go into detail about how exactly to set up a phonegap application, or how to get started with Rails. I&amp;rsquo;ll leave that as an exercise to the reader, but also you can clone my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/borego/progressive_enhancement_phonegap&#34;&gt;github repo&lt;/a&gt; which has all of that (and many other things) done for you. You&amp;rsquo;ll also need to, for the purpose of this demo, add the Contacts plugin to your Phonegap app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-1-point-your-phonegap-app-at-your-web-app-a-name-content-href-content-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 1) Point your Phonegap app at your web app &lt;a name=&#34;content&#34; href=&#34;#content&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This step seems a bit trivial, but it&amp;rsquo;s not part of the default Phonegap configuration. In your &lt;code&gt;www/config.xml&lt;/code&gt; file, add the following line:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-xml&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;content src=&amp;quot;http://your-site-name-here.com&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the example repo, the path is replaced with &lt;code&gt;http://prog-enh-pg.herokuapp.com/&lt;/code&gt;, as that&amp;rsquo;s where the heroku app lives for the demo. I usually put it after the &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;author&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; tag as well, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think that&amp;rsquo;s required.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-2-modify-the-user-agent-coming-out-of-your-pg-app-a-name-useragent-href-useragent-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 2) Modify the User Agent coming out of your PG app &lt;a name=&#34;userAgent&#34; href=&#34;#userAgent&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is basically the only part that&amp;rsquo;s platform-specific. Obviously the way you do this on Android is going to differ from the way you do it on iOS. This guide only details the Android one, but it would be just as easy to do in iOS (or Windows Phone).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Navigate down to &lt;code&gt;platforms/android/src/path/to/your/app/ProjectName.java&lt;/code&gt; and edit the onCreate function to look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-java&#34;&gt;public void onCreate(Bundle savedInstanceState)
{
    super.onCreate(savedInstanceState);
    super.init();
    // Set by &amp;lt;content src=&amp;quot;index.html&amp;quot;&amp;gt; in config.xml
    super.loadUrl(Config.getStartUrl());

    ////// This is what you edit //////
    String ua = this.appView.getSettings().getUserAgentString();
    this.appView.getSettings().setUserAgentString(ua + &amp;quot; phonegap_prog_enh&amp;quot;);
    //super.loadUrl(&amp;quot;file:///android_asset/www/index.html&amp;quot;);
    ////// This is what you edit //////
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bold text is what you&amp;rsquo;re adding. All this does is append a custom string (in this case, &lt;code&gt;&amp;quot;phonegap_prog_enh&amp;quot;&lt;/code&gt;) to the User Agent so that you can determine on the server side whether or not a use is on your app or not. Yes, of course, someone could probably proxy this and sniff it out, or reverse engineer it, but it doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter - all it would do is break the app in their browser. Trollers gonna troll.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-3-listen-for-your-custom-user-agent-on-the-server-side-and-set-a-flag-a-name-flag-href-flag-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 3) Listen for your custom User Agent on the server side and set a flag &lt;a name=&#34;flag&#34; href=&#34;#flag&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that we have a way to know if a user is accessing our server via a normal browser or via our Phonegap app, we can decide whether or not to enable Phonegap-specific features. You need to do this because if you don&amp;rsquo;t, you get some &lt;a href=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/prog-enh-phonegap/uglypg.png&#34;&gt;ugly error messages&lt;/a&gt; as the web app tries to access Phonegap APIs that aren&amp;rsquo;t there. This detection is really easy, though. In the sample app, it looks like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-ruby&#34;&gt;class ContactsController &amp;lt; ApplicationController
  def index
    @phonegap = request.env[&#39;HTTP_USER_AGENT&#39;].include?(&amp;quot;phonegap_prog_enh&amp;quot;)
  end
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which then falls through to the view, where we can do stuff like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;% if @phonegap %&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;h3&amp;gt;Only Phonegap users will see this&amp;lt;/h3&amp;gt;
  ... 
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re only going to want the Phonegap Javascript to fire in these instances, which leads us to the next part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-4-enable-phonegap-specific-functionality-a-name-enhance-href-enhance-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 4) Enable Phonegap-specific functionality &lt;a name=&#34;enhance&#34; href=&#34;#enhance&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned above, you&amp;rsquo;re not going to want the Phonegap code to run willy-nilly all over your application. Specifically, the &lt;code&gt;cordova.js&lt;/code&gt; file (which normally lives in your Phonegap&amp;rsquo;s &lt;code&gt;platforms/android/assets/www&lt;/code&gt; folder) is what kicks off all of the Phonegap functionality, so once you load that, you&amp;rsquo;re going down that path. Luckily, this is easily avoided:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;% if @phonegap %&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;script src=&amp;quot;/cordova.js&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
  &amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot;&amp;gt;
    // your PG-specific code here
  &amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;% end %&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously you don&amp;rsquo;t need to inline your PG Javascript, but you do need to protect against &lt;code&gt;cordova.js&lt;/code&gt; loading out of place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;step-5-profit-a-name-profit-href-profit-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Step 5) Profit &lt;a name=&#34;profit&#34; href=&#34;#profit&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s pretty much it. Obviously there&amp;rsquo;s a lot more to it when it comes to the actual Phonegap APIs, but there&amp;rsquo;s a lot of support and writing about all of that. The point of this guide is just to lay out this methodology, and to further prove my belief that the vast majority of app development can be done with &amp;ldquo;hybrid&amp;rdquo; apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;gotchas-a-name-gotchas-href-gotchas-i-class-ion-link-i-a:b24c23782d00ece4bee8e2115b865429&#34;&gt;Gotchas &lt;a name=&#34;gotchas&#34; href=&#34;#gotchas&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all know it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a real tech article without some gotchas, so here are some things that tripped me up the first few times.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to listen for both the DOM to be ready and the Phonegap APIs to be ready. This takes the form of &lt;code&gt;&#39;DOMContentLoaded&#39;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;&#39;deviceready&#39;&lt;/code&gt; event listeners. It&amp;rsquo;s as easy as setting a flag in each that you can reference later when trying to run your PG code. You can also just check if the &lt;code&gt;navigator.[insert-plugin-name]&lt;/code&gt; exists yet (probably safer).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to put &lt;code&gt;cordova.js&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;cordova_plugins.js&lt;/code&gt;, and the &lt;code&gt;/plugins&lt;/code&gt; directory in the right place on your server. You should be able to do it from a relative path based on where you access &lt;code&gt;cordova.js&lt;/code&gt;, but for the purpose of this demo, everything is in the &lt;code&gt;/public&lt;/code&gt; folder for Rails.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Any time you add or remove a plugin via Phonegap&amp;rsquo;s CLI, you need to go back and update at least the &lt;code&gt;cordova_plugins.js&lt;/code&gt; file that&amp;rsquo;s on your server. Not doing so will either produce some funky errors (as it tries to look for a plugin that doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist), or it won&amp;rsquo;t give you access to the APIs you want.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to shoot an email, tweet, or reach out to me any other way with questions, feedback, etc. Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>phonegap,progressive enhancement,hybrid app,rails,java,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open Letter to OkCupid</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/an-open-letter-to-okcupid</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/open-letter-okcupid/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2013 17:11:40 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/an-open-letter-to-okcupid</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;OkCupid is great, but it&amp;rsquo;s broken.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Fixing it should be pretty easy &amp;emdash; just give a fast, simple way to stop bad members from being bad, and let the community sort it out.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Empower your users and they&amp;rsquo;ll empower you.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dear OkCupid,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love you. Well, maybe not so much love anymore. I really like you. I really like how you&amp;rsquo;ve made your services free for everyone, and how you&amp;rsquo;re helping people connect and meet others that they never would. I absolutely love how you use your data to create &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.okcupid.com&#34;&gt;interesting and relevant blog posts&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;rsquo;m also a firm believer in the company and your mission, especially after hearing CEO and co-founder Sam Yagan &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.capitalentrepreneurs.com/tonight-wisconsin-startup-night-techstars/&#34;&gt;give a talk a few weeks back&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why I feel like I have to do this. See, there&amp;rsquo;s something wrong. It&amp;rsquo;s not a major problem (although, given the userbase and intertia you have, it might be, but given your &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.crazyblinddate.com/&#34;&gt;willingness&lt;/a&gt; to try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.okcupid.com/mybestface&#34;&gt;experiments&lt;/a&gt; and side-projects, this might be something you can spin up/spin off), but it has some pretty significant consequences. As we&amp;rsquo;ve been made well aware by the internet, there are &lt;a href=&#34;http://theinternetisterrible.com/&#34;&gt;lots of terrible people&lt;/a&gt; out there. Humanity can be pretty messed up. OkCupid is, unfortunately, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.mandatory.com/2012/11/13/ok-cupid-an-exploration-into-just-how-low-some-guys-will-go&#34;&gt;no safe haven&lt;/a&gt; to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.tumblr.com/tagged/nice%20guys%20of%20okcupid&#34;&gt;denizens of the internet&lt;/a&gt;. OkCupid&amp;rsquo;s design, however, makes it possible for these baddies to exploit the system, which is where our problem lies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;signal-vs-noise-a-name-signal-href-signal-i-class-ion-link-i-a:4c0c4bbe7a08bf9aa64c3401696272b2&#34;&gt;Signal vs. Noise &lt;a name=&#34;signal&#34; href=&#34;#signal&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the uninitiated, the way OkCupid works is that users sign up, answer some profile questions about themselves, list some information, post some pictures, state what they&amp;rsquo;re interested in, and maybe even answer some of OkCupid&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Match Questions&amp;rdquo;, which is where its famed matchmaking service comes from. Users then have the ability to send messages to any other user, under the premise of making an introduction, conversation, or whatever they please.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Any user. An infinite number of messages and an infinite number of messages. For all users on OkCupid. And yes, you can talk about anything. Sound suspicious? Maybe not at first. The same is true of most social networks - anyone can send anyone a Facebook message, or Tweet at any other user, etc. The problem comes at a combination of context and this availability. OkCupid is a dating site. Apparently, some (too many) guys think this gives them license to harass girls, to solicit unwanted relations, and to do this to hundreds of girls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sounds pretty grim for ladies, right? They sign up looking for some fun dates, maybe even Mr. Right, and they&amp;rsquo;re bombarded by one-liners, solicitations for sex, and some that are just plain weird. This is bad, because getting lots of creepy/unwanted messages means girls just get overwhelmed and/or disgruntled, and leave. This is something you&amp;rsquo;ve even mentioned and analyzed yourself in &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/the-mathematics-of-beauty/&#34;&gt;an old blog post&lt;/a&gt;. So this drives women away, this is bad, right? It gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of forcing women away, this endless inundation desensitizes them to receiving messages in the first place, which means, for any halfway decent guy out there, actually getting through to a girl is that much harder. The number of messages guys have to send to get any responses is absurd, with&amp;nbsp;&lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.okcupid.com/index.php/online-dating-advice-exactly-what-to-say-in-a-first-message/&#34;&gt;response rates hovering around 30%&lt;/a&gt;. 30%! Mostly because (bad) guys send way too many messages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;okay-now-what-a-name-solution-href-solution-i-class-ion-link-i-a:4c0c4bbe7a08bf9aa64c3401696272b2&#34;&gt;Okay. Now what? &lt;a name=&#34;solution&#34; href=&#34;#solution&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So this is bad. Some guys are ruining it for all of us, guys and gals included. What do we do, then? Sit and whine about it? Try &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.eharmony.com/&#34;&gt;one&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ourtime.com/&#34;&gt;of&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.chemistry.com/&#34;&gt;the&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.zoosk.com/&#34;&gt;many&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.match.com/index.aspx&#34;&gt;other&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;/span&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.pof.com/&#34;&gt;mostly&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.christianmingle.com/&#34;&gt;terrible&lt;/a&gt;) &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.benaughty.com/&#34;&gt;dating&lt;/a&gt; sites? Go back to our old ways of bars, clubs, parties, and other social events? Give up and start our own online dating site/service? Try one of those &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.onlulu.com/&#34;&gt;newfangled&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://swoonapp.com/&#34;&gt;dating&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://blendr.com/&#34; &gt;apps&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gotinder.com/index.html&#34;&gt;that&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://grindr.com/&#34;&gt;are&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://coffeemeetsbagel.com/&#34;&gt;now&lt;/a&gt; (or at least, for now) all the rage? I don&amp;rsquo;t want to do that, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want me to do that. So let&amp;rsquo;s figure out how to work it out.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two things that I think would do a lot to fix this problem. Of course, there are ways around it, but how many guys are really that persitent (don&amp;rsquo;t answer that - I&amp;rsquo;m afraid of the answer). They aren&amp;rsquo;t even that hard to do/implement, and they should naturally weed out the bad ones pretty quickly. Ready? They aren&amp;rsquo;t exactly groundbreaking, but I&amp;rsquo;ll give justification for each.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Limit the number of outgoing messages over a certain period (e.g. 3/day? 5/day? etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allow users to give feedback/behavior ratings to other users (a la karma?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Okay, I actually have 3, but it&amp;rsquo;s just a variation  - Have a system where the number of outstanding messages you can have at one time is dependent upon your rating (e.g. if you send a lot of bad messages, you lose points/those messages, but if you send some good messages but the recipient just isn&amp;rsquo;t interested, you can still redeem that message))&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rocket surgery, right? Here&amp;rsquo;s why they&amp;rsquo;re good ideas. The first is obvious - restricting the volume cuts down on the amount of messages anyone has to deal with. It also makes everyone think harder about and be more selective with those messages they send. From a business perspective, this might be bad for OkCupid, as it&amp;rsquo;s likely to drive traffic away from their site (i.e. to email/text, but that happens anyway), but it&amp;rsquo;s probably the easiest way to cut down on the flood. The hottest girls will still get the majority of messages, but it&amp;rsquo;s still less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second allows the community to self-select the decent guys out from the garbage. If you get a bad message from someone, you&amp;rsquo;re virtually powerless. At most, girls can block guys, preventing them from sending further messages. This does nothing to their ability to harass the rest of the community, though, leaving that scummy guy to run amok. If there were a way for the collective voice to say bad things about guys, girls would have an easier way to sift through the noise, and allow the quality to float to the top (a la Reddit).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third is personally my favorite, but also the hardest to implement and to make fair/balanced. Each person gets a set amount of messages per day, based on their rating. Messages that get a nice vote, or even a reply, raise that person&amp;rsquo;s rating and/or replenish their message count. The count also rebuilds itself over time. Quora does something similar to this with its Credits system. Good answers on Quora give Credits, which can be spent on promotions and whatnot. The credits also replenish themselves over time, so users aren&amp;rsquo;t left out to dry. OkCupid could really benefit from something like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still have faith in you, OkCupid. You do great things, and you&amp;rsquo;re way better than any other site I&amp;rsquo;ve used, both in terms of user experience and user base. Just please, please fix these things, and I&amp;rsquo;ll love you even more. I&amp;rsquo;m more than happy to talk about this in further detail and clarify some points if you&amp;rsquo;d like, as this post was already getting too long to go into full detail.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>okcupid,messaging,online dating,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trinker</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/trinker</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/trinker/landing.png</image>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2013 15:10:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/trinker</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:5c8d1c0ac174c2b9af11e2912b72ae28&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trinker is a service that simplifies your social life by providing an easy, secure way to share your nightlife activities, keep track of your drinking buddies, see what parts of town are hoppin&amp;rsquo;, and even save you some cash. Trinker represents my first foray into entrepreneurship, and has been a constant source of inspiration, energy, and learning for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trinker was first brought to life through conversations with Rob Brooks, a good friend of mine, and when we decided to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;http://madison.startupweekend.org/2012/04/28/game-on/&#34;&gt;Startup Weekend: Madison 2012&lt;/a&gt;. Armed with the skeleton of a back-end I&amp;rsquo;d built on PHP and MongoDB, and my knowledge of jQuery Mobile, I set my team out to do as much validation as possible while I threw together as much of a functional prototype as I could based on what Rob and I had sketched out. I actually invented the Trinker logo when hailing a team after giving the 60-second pitch on Friday night, and designed our first business cards that night.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After running into some severe performance limitations with jQuery Mobile, and being inspired by Assanka&amp;rsquo;s (now FT Labs) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iZA4t5MmRBY&#34;&gt;Financial Times&lt;/a&gt; mobile app, I decided to re-design the app and re-write the front-end using vanilla Javascript and CSS. This was my first foray into mobile web development as well, and due to my relative inexperience with Javascript at the time, I ran into a lot of issues, and ultimately decided this approach wasn&amp;rsquo;t sustainable and went about re-writing it a third time using &lt;a href=&#34;http://yuilibrary.com/&#34;&gt;YUI&lt;/a&gt; and a new back-end built on top of Ruby on Rails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, that was about the time my two team members had to move away from Madison for work, and I ran out of steam on the project, so Trinker has laid dormant for approximately a year. However, a new business model has breathed some life and inspiration into me, so don&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if you see this app running around Madison bars soon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-images:5c8d1c0ac174c2b9af11e2912b72ae28&#34;&gt;Selected Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Landing Page:
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/trinker/landing.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/trinker/t1.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/trinker/t2.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/trinker/t3.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>entrepreneurship,app design,yui,jquery mobile,startup,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Flow</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-flow</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/importance-of-flow/header.jpg</image>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 16:38:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-flow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pop-ups are distracting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Design your life to have less sudden distractions and you&amp;rsquo;ll be more productive and happier.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Desiging user experiences that encourage flow are good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become more and more interested in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&#34;&gt;Flow &lt;/a&gt;recently. As a psych major, flow is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of for a long time, but I always thought of it as something that just happens, and never gave it much thought. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until an unrelated talk by former psych professor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psych.rochester.edu/people/deci_edward/index.html&#34;&gt;Ed Deci&lt;/a&gt; I was listening to a few months ago that got me thinking about flow in the context of UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that Prof. Deci said that got me thinking was actually about humanistic psychotherapy. Deci studies motivation, and is co-creator of the esteemed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.selfdeterminationtheory.org/&#34;&gt;Self-Determination Theory&lt;/a&gt;. What SDT/Deci says is that intrinsic motivation is inherent in people, and it is the product of a situation that features of set of characteristics (autonomy, competence, relatedness). It is also possible (and unfortunately, very common) to thwart these needs, which leads to poor mental health, lack of motivation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concidentally, research has shown a fairly high overlap between the conditions for flow and the basis of SDT. Flow requires a level of challenge that is adequately matched to the abilities of the participant (competence), the activity must have clear goals an progress (relatedness - sort of), and the task must present clear, immediate, and constant feedback, so that the participant can adjust performance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mihaly_Csikszentmihalyi&#34;&gt;Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;cheek-sent-mee-hah-yee&amp;rdquo;), a world leader in flow, published this graph to express the relationship between challenge and skill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/importance-of-flow/challenge-vs-skill.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also things that can absolutely ruin flow, which is actually the motivation behind this post. I have a new worst enemy when it comes to reading stories on some popular news sites/blogs, and it&amp;rsquo;s this thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/importance-of-flow/comment-box.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate this thing so much. Any time I&amp;rsquo;m reading a news story on TechCrunch, I&amp;rsquo;m usually immersed in the experience and enjoying the read until this little thing pops up in the lower right of my browser window. Its sudden appearance grabs my attention, and I instinctively look at it. After that, I murmur something under my breath and then go ba-&amp;hellip;wait, where was I? What was I just reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a major disturbance, as I quickly regain my concentration and get back to reading, but with new/popular articles, this happens several times during my read. This little blip in concentration - a break in my flow - slows me down and sullies my experience. This happens to us all the time, what with cell phones buzzing and Facebook notifications popping up and emails rolling in constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>flow,psychology,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Heatmap &amp; Remote Sensing</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/foursquare-heatmap--remote-sensing</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/posts/foursquare-heatmap/header.png</image>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 17:21:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/foursquare-heatmap--remote-sensing</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Foursquare&amp;rsquo;s API and Google Maps are pretty easy to work with.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Creating a new product can be as easy as combining two existing technologies.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;New products create opportunities for new experiences.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A little over a month ago (technically during the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hackerleague.org/hackathons/foursquare-hackathon-2013&#34;&gt;Foursquare Hackathon&lt;/a&gt;, but I was working from home due to &lt;a href=&#34;http://midwestultimate.com/red-eye&#34;&gt;Red Eye&lt;/a&gt;) I spent a few hours one weekend hacking together an idea I&amp;rsquo;d come up with when working on Foursquare integration for &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettrinker.com&#34;&gt;Trinker&lt;/a&gt;. What I discovered while playing with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.foursquare.com/overview/venues&#34;&gt;Venues API&lt;/a&gt; is that with one query, you can get all of the information about a bunch of different venues (I think it tops out at 30). Part of that information is, of course, the location (latitude, longitude, address), and another interesting data point: the &lt;code&gt;hereNow&lt;/code&gt; value.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What that means is that with a single query to the Foursquare API, I essentially have a list of locations and how many people are checked in at that location right now. Interesting, I thought. So then I thought, why don&amp;rsquo;t I take this information and create an overlay in Google Maps? A heat map, if you will? Well, the idea sat around for a month or two, and when I caught wind of the Foursquare Hackathon thanks to &lt;a href=&#34;http://snowshoestamp.com&#34;&gt;Snowshoe&lt;/a&gt;, I decided it was time to dust that one off.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-technical-details-a-name-tech-href-tech-i-class-ion-link-i-a:8c66a7351b15f2ef68d2e9b9363a058c&#34;&gt;The technical details &lt;a name=&#34;tech&#34; href=&#34;#tech&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is written entirely in Javascript (there&amp;rsquo;s no server-side code behind this - no database), and uses Foursquare&amp;rsquo;s API and Google&amp;rsquo;s Maps API. I first try to capture the user&amp;rsquo;s geolocation data (&lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Using_geolocation&#34;&gt;navigator.geolocation&lt;/a&gt;) so I can display a map that&amp;rsquo;s immediately relevant to them. If that fails (or they deny), I default to NYC (as it almost always has data to show). Users can also enter an address or location which I then run through Google&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/geocoding/&#34;&gt;Geocoder API&lt;/a&gt; and pull out the lat/lng which go on to the 4sq/gMaps functions. Once I have a lat/lng, I make an AJAX call to Foursquare with credentials (&lt;code&gt;client_id&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;client_secret&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;version #&lt;/code&gt;) and the data to make the query (&lt;code&gt;radius&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;lat&lt;/code&gt;/&lt;code&gt;lng&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;category&lt;/code&gt;, etc). The return from that gives me the &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.foursquare.com/docs/explore#req=venues/search%3Fll%3D40.7,-74&#34;&gt;venues list&lt;/a&gt; (&lt;code&gt;data.response.venues&lt;/code&gt;), which I save off into a local variable for later (&lt;code&gt;venueList&lt;/code&gt;). Once I have all the data, I initialize a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/reference#Map&#34;&gt;&lt;code&gt;google.maps.Map&lt;/code&gt; object&lt;/a&gt; (with some &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/reference#MapOptions&#34;&gt;options&lt;/a&gt;), and then iterate through each of the venues, drawing a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/reference#Circle&#34;&gt;circle&lt;/a&gt; with radius and color based on the &lt;code&gt;hereNow&lt;/code&gt; value of that venue. Once the circle is drawn to the map (which is kind of weird - you actually create a new circle with a reference to the map object), I add a &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/events&#34;&gt;click listener&lt;/a&gt; to display the venue information, and then I add them to the table below which I then run through &lt;a href=&#34;http://tablesorter.com/docs/&#34;&gt;tablesorter&lt;/a&gt;. When you click on one of the table rows, I grab the lat/lng from that row and search through the list of venues (&lt;code&gt;venueList&lt;/code&gt;) to find the one that matches and open up an &lt;a href=&#34;https://developers.google.com/maps/documentation/javascript/reference#InfoWindow&#34;&gt;info window&lt;/a&gt; to display its content. Voila.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whew, okay. That was a mouthful. For the non-tech folk, basically all I&amp;rsquo;m doing is getting the latitude and longitude of your current location (or what you type in), querying Foursquare, pulling out the info, and putting circles onto Google Maps based on how many people are at the locations, which you can then click on to get more info. You can also sort the table below, and click on any row to see that location on the map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;but-why-brad-a-name-why-href-why-i-class-ion-link-i-a:8c66a7351b15f2ef68d2e9b9363a058c&#34;&gt;But why, Brad? &lt;a name=&#34;why&#34; href=&#34;#why&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it&amp;rsquo;s cool. That&amp;rsquo;s actually the first motivation. I had the idea and I wanted to see if I could pull it off. It turns out I could, and it only took me a few hours to get the base prototype working. I thought it&amp;rsquo;d be interesting to literally see where people are. That is, in essence, what this is. I&amp;rsquo;ve created an interactive information visualization of where people are, according to Foursquare. And it&amp;rsquo;s really cool. I&amp;rsquo;ve also made a few &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLq3M6ODce1N6IZoXoisCw5WHjEQs7SAWl&amp;amp;feature=view_all&#34;&gt;time lapse videos&lt;/a&gt; to show how cool it can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve also noticed something else, though, since making this. Every now and then, I get curious to see what the map looks like. I&amp;rsquo;m curious to see what people are doing in places I&amp;rsquo;m not. I now have a tool that lets me see this, and the fact that there are real people out there making these things happen is a pretty interesting experience. When I have friends on vacation, or travelling to different cities, I jokingly tell them I&amp;rsquo;ll be watching them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s also a practical use to this technology, which is part of the motivation behind building it - I can see where people are/aren&amp;rsquo;t in my immediate vicinity. If I&amp;rsquo;m planning to go out to the bars, or out to a restaurant, and I see there are a lot of people in a certain area, maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll want to avoid there (or to go there).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the very least, it&amp;rsquo;s fun to play with!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;timelapse-a-name-timelapse-href-timelapse-i-class-ion-link-i-a:8c66a7351b15f2ef68d2e9b9363a058c&#34;&gt;Timelapse &lt;a name=&#34;timelapse&#34; href=&#34;#timelapse&#34;&gt;&lt;i class=&#34;ion-link&#34;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can see a few timelapse videos of various cities/locations below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/videoseries?list=PLq3M6ODce1N6IZoXoisCw5WHjEQs7SAWl&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
      <tags>foursquare,heatmap,remote sensing,javascript,</tags>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebradog</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/case-study/zebradog</link>
      <image>https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/storystation.png</image>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/case-study/zebradog</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about:58aa00a3f9ec4cc7a62166ecd695ef26&#34;&gt;About&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zebradog is an environmental graphic design firm located in Madison, WI who specializes in creating immersive, branded experiences for their clients. Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s multidisciplinary team of architects, graphic designers, and software developers blend the physical and digital realms, creating novel digital applications of technology for interactive multimedia and website design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working with Zebradog gave me the opportunity to work with an extremely talented team as well as push the limits of  web technology in the interactive multimedia space. During my time at Zebradog, we made the decision to move away from the technology the company had previously used (Quartz Composer) and toward embracing the developing world of web technology, which lead us to experiment with a lot of new technology, such as Three.js (for WebGL), Zigfu (for Kinect), and many Javascript touch libraries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other branch of Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s Digital Team built beautiful, well-structured, and  highly usable websites for clients. Built mainly on Drupal, ZD&amp;rsquo;s sites traditionally had not been responsive or mobile-friendly, which is another point I stressed while working with ZD. Mid-State Technical College serves as an example of the first mobile-first design project Zebradog completed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videos can be found on &lt;a href=&#34;http://vimeo.com/zebradog&#34;&gt;Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s Vimeo page&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;http://demo.zebradog.com&#34;&gt;Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s Demo page&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;selected-images:58aa00a3f9ec4cc7a62166ecd695ef26&#34;&gt;Selected Images&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/storystation.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/hometownheroes.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/aramco.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/nw.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/northwestern.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/mstc-desktop.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/mstc-tablet.png&#34; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/case-study/zebradog/mstc-phone.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <tags>interactive multimedia,website,design,kinect,kiosk,</tags>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
