<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meta on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://hugo.spf13.com/tags/meta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meta on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 14:21:58 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://hugo.spf13.com/tags/meta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Content</title>
      <link>http://hugo.spf13.com/2012-12-content</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Dec 2012 14:21:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.spf13.com/2012-12-content</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m going to say this straight out of the gates: this blog post is kind of a cop-out. There have been a ton of changes in my life lately, so I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little MIA when it comes to this blog. One of the things I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to do, though, finally (~3 months after launching the new site) is to populate my portfolio a bit more so people have stuff to look at. People like looking at stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a handful of new entries for web and media projects I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on with &lt;a href=&#34;http://zebradog.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Zebradog&lt;/a&gt;, one or two freelance/side-project pieces, and a whole slew of dance items. Art is still forthcoming, as is any updates on &lt;a href=&#34;http://gettrinker.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Trinker&lt;/a&gt; (we&amp;rsquo;ve had a big month, and February will continue to be so).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content is, however, one of the pieces of UX that I neglect the most. I&amp;rsquo;m always an advocate for designing with the content in mind, but I usually write it off as &amp;ldquo;some text&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;an image and some text&amp;rdquo;, or some generalization of what the content actually is. The volume of content is incredibly important, and can really make or break a design if appropriate consideration isn&amp;rsquo;t taken. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of material out there about content strategy, so that would probably be a good place to look if you wanted to brush up on it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site!</title>
      <link>http://hugo.spf13.com/2012-11-new-site</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 17:32:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hugo.spf13.com/2012-11-new-site</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It only took me about 10 months, but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to rebuilding this site to have a purpose. I originally built a personal website when I was leaving Epic with the intention of having a place to show my past work as well as a place to play around with new technologies on the web. That was, at least, the intention. If any of you were keeping tabs on it, that never actually happened. I built the site haphazardly over the course of a few days and never updated it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time around, though, it&amp;rsquo;ll be different. Two main reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I built the site on top of Drupal this time around instead of doing everything by hand. This means I&amp;rsquo;m not trying to be a whizkid web developer anymore (read: more professional) and it also means updating things is a lot easier/less painful.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I have a reason and method of keeping it up to date. If I&amp;rsquo;m blogging about usability/user experience, it&amp;rsquo;s an excuse to keep on top of things, and to keep it fresh. Plus, if I want to be a consultant, I&amp;rsquo;ve gotta show my stuff somehow, right?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do have to give a fair bit of credit to my &lt;a href=&#34;https://zebradog.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ZD&lt;/a&gt; family for both inspiring me and giving me some experience building sites from scratch on top of Drupal. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be where I am today (both in terms of skills and motivation) if not for them, and I&amp;rsquo;m looking forward to each new day with ZD.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a few ideas of blog post themes/threads (Design in the Wild, War Stories, etc.), but this blog will also likely be a mixture of professional, personal, and possibly-insane. It&amp;rsquo;ll be fun to work on it, see it grow, populate my portfolio, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Onward and upward.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>