<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>transparency on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/transparency/</link>
    <description>Recent content in transparency on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 13:54:44 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/transparency/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open (Love) Letter To My Next Work Partner</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 13:54:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Transparency is paramount. Make sure there are stated objectives (even if they&#39;re inaccurate), daily check-ins, and quarterly reviews. Flexibility empowers your people to do the best work they can. Have a bias against policies, rules, and meetings. Trust is your most powerful tool. Get a bunch of good people together, point them in a direction, and get out of the way.   One of the myriad benefits of having spent so much time working as a contractor is the variety of cultures, work practices, and methodologies employed by various companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transparency of &#34;Online&#34;</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jul 2014 17:37:34 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/transparency-of-online/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Notification design is important, especially in the light of ubiquitous computing. Designing to allow interrupted attention is crucial. Context matters: Users are no longer in a room at a desk on a computer.   With all the talk about unplugging, disconnecting, screen time, and going &amp;ldquo;off the grid&amp;rdquo;, there&amp;rsquo;s clearly been a shift in the way we interact with technology and the implications it has for society (as well as possibly our mental health).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>