<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Performing Design on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/performing-design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Performing Design on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:19:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/performing-design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Improvisation, Creativity, and Design</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2018 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/improvisation-creativity-and-design/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
I’m certainly not the first person to write about the role of improv in creative processes, its value in broadening ways of thinking, creating general good-feelings (which, interestingly, go hand-in-hand), etc. However, the majority of what’s been written so far pertains to using improv exercises in group dynamics and doesn’t address its potential as a design tool.
Part of the inspiration behind this post is my recent participation in one of Improv Everywhere’s “MP3 Experiments”, in which a massive number of strangers volunteer to interact with a recorded set of instructions in a public space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of (Daily) Technique</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-daily-technique/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 May 2018 17:15:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/the-importance-of-daily-technique/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
As professional artists, we’re expected to practice our craft every single day. For dancers, the main way to do this is to spend time in class (for most of us, that’s every day, if not several times a day; full-time dancers are usually in class or in the studio 6–10 hours per day, 5–6 days a week). Aside from the physical exercise (which is an important element for performing artists), all of this time spent doing roughly the same thing has many benefits and side-effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Intro to Embodied Cognition</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Apr 2018 14:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-intro-to-embodied-cognition/</guid>
      <description>Originally posted on performing.design
Underneath a lot of what we cover in performing.design is embodied cognition, a fairly recent development psychology and cognitive science. Embodied Cognition seeks to explore the relationship between how we use our bodies and how we think/what our brains do. It’s about looking at a thinking organism holistically as opposed to focusing on the brain, including the motor system, perceptual system, and the body’s interaction with the current environment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>