<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Website on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/website/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Website on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebradog</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/zebradog/</guid>
      <description>About Zebradog is an environmental graphic design firm located in Madison, WI who specializes in creating immersive, branded experiences for their clients. Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s multidisciplinary team of architects, graphic designers, and software developers blend the physical and digital realms, creating novel digital applications of technology for interactive multimedia and website design.
Working with Zebradog gave me the opportunity to work with an extremely talented team as well as push the limits of web technology in the interactive multimedia space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Design Studio Etc</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/design-studio-etc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 14:42:59 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/design-studio-etc/</guid>
      <description>About Design Studio Etc. (&amp;ldquo;etc&amp;rdquo;) is an architectural design firm headquarted in Madison, WI with over 30 years of design and consulting experience. etc&amp;rsquo;s work is featured all over Madison, greater Wisconsin, and even other areas of the country such as Illinois, Arizona, and California.
etc&amp;rsquo;s former website was a flat set of three pages which left the user with virtually no idea of what the company actually was/did. The &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; page was the only way to glean any real information, and the design was dominated by an image that had very little value-add.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>inspireDANCE Dance Festival</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/inspiredance-dance-festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Feb 2011 15:10:01 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/inspiredance-dance-festival/</guid>
      <description>About The inspireDANCE Festival is the result of Arielle Friedlander&amp;rsquo;s 2010 KEY Project at the University of Rochester. As an ogoing festival, inspireDANCE&amp;rsquo;s goals are to strengthen the dance community in Rochester by connecting students to professional dancers in and around the Rochester area. The Festival features professional dancers and instructors from Rochester as well as a feature artist with national (and sometimes world) renown. Past artists include Bill Evans, Clyde Evans, Jr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>