<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Process on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/process/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Process on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:19:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/process/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a UX Department from scratch at a 20-year-old Big Data Company</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jul 2019 10:19:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/building-a-ux-department-from-scratch-at-a-20-year-old-big-data-company/</guid>
      <description>Originally written for 1010data&amp;rsquo;s UX Blog
These stories usually start with some sort of “when I first heard about ___”, but in this case, that goes much further back than a) the story usually goes, and b) is really practical. 1010data has been around since 2000 and has gone through tremendous growth and change as an organization since then. Recently, we’ve embarked on a new set of changes.
Document the process  There are two things I hear time and time again when telling friends, family, and colleagues about what I’m doing at 1010:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Designers Need to Know About Development</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 01:59:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/what-designers-need-to-know-about-development/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s a lot of discussion around whether designers should code. Here&#39;s my take on it. Short answer: No, but you should be aware of the technology. As a designer, having at least a vague idea of how the technology behind the products you&#39;re working on is beneficial, both in terms of the design work you do and in communicating with other team members. There may be certain quirks based on implementation, but overall the pattern is Database -- Server-side -- (API) -- (Middleware) -- Front-End -- Visual/UI Design   It seems that everyone has an opinion on whether designers should code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Open (Love) Letter To My Next Work Partner</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Jun 2017 13:54:44 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/an-open-love-letter-to-my-next-work-partner/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Transparency is paramount. Make sure there are stated objectives (even if they&#39;re inaccurate), daily check-ins, and quarterly reviews. Flexibility empowers your people to do the best work they can. Have a bias against policies, rules, and meetings. Trust is your most powerful tool. Get a bunch of good people together, point them in a direction, and get out of the way.   One of the myriad benefits of having spent so much time working as a contractor is the variety of cultures, work practices, and methodologies employed by various companies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do&#39;s and Don&#39;ts of Corporate Innovation</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/dos-and-donts-of-corporate-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Apr 2017 15:23:55 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/dos-and-donts-of-corporate-innovation/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  There&#39;s a ton of potential in the corporate innovation world, and as the venture market cools, the future of early stage might be corporate. Innovation teams need certain special rules and freedoms compared to the core business, especially in highly regulated industries. Culture and environment are the most important things to define and develop in these settings. Don&#39;t settle, and don&#39;t let corporate culture interfere.   As some of you may know, I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending some time working in the corporate innovation team of a Fortune 500 company.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>