<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Usability Research on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/usability-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Usability Research on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:58:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/usability-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Research Checklist</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:58:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  A lot more goes into designing and running your own usability tests than people typically think. Being properly prepared can be the difference between great success and catastrophic failure for your user research. Don&#39;t underestimate how much time, energy, and resource setting up a proper usability study takes.   MobileIgniter asked me to put together a checklist of everything needed to properly set up and run studies in a usability lab.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Family Insurance</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/american-family-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/american-family-insurance/</guid>
      <description>About {{ .Description }} {{ partial &amp;ldquo;nda.html&amp;rdquo; .}}</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candorem</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</guid>
      <description>About Since Candorem’s inception in 2010, they’ve had the privilege of providing strategic marketing solutions for a wide range of organizations including American Family Insurance, Better Business Bureau of Wisconsin, Verlo Mattress, Process Retail Group, and Henry Vilas Zoo among others. Located in Lake Mills, WI (between Madison and Milwaukee), Candorem has won several awards in recent years, including a project I assisted research and design for, Transform Milwaukee.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextt</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:11:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</guid>
      <description>Background Nextt was a collaborative social planning tool. Nextt&amp;rsquo;s goal was to make it easier to plan social events for 4-10 people within the next 14 days, and the service did so by allowing users to create and share event Ideas that, once the date/time, location, and attendees were finalized, transitioned into a Plan. If the Idea did not reach fruition within a preset amount of time, it would self-destruct, forcing the user to take action.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>