<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>usability research on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/tags/usability-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in usability research on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:58:43 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/tags/usability-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Usability Research Checklist</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Aug 2017 15:58:43 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/usability-research-checklist/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  A lot more goes into designing and running your own usability tests than people typically think. Being properly prepared can be the difference between great success and catastrophic failure for your user research. Don&#39;t underestimate how much time, energy, and resource setting up a proper usability study takes.   Update 4/30/2018 This content used to be publicly available, but a more-in-depth version is now available for purchase via MelioraLabs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Family Insurance</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/american-family-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2017 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/american-family-insurance/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Candorem</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2014 11:12:46 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/candorem/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  You can learn a ton while on lunch break by asking the right questions/giving the right instructions and sending it off for remote unmoderated testing. A properly orchestrated user-centered/iterative design process can provide value for many projects, including marketing websites. Although it was early in my career and the mentorship was useful, I much prefer full-blown applications to these types of eCommerce/marketing/brochure sites that Candorem is known for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nextt</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 2014 15:11:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/showcase/nextt/</guid>
      <description>Lessons Learned  Never underestimate the value of guerrilla UX research. Instead of spending hours debating something internally, put together a survey and put it on Reddit. Use the resources and data available to you. Utilizing a well-defined analytics suite to define funnels and focus on problem points and in-depth user research to discover why people are falling off at that point can have tremendous impacts on conversion/success rates. Mark&#39;s postmortem covers a lot of what we learned and expresses similar sentiments to what I had as we closed down Nextt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>