<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>http://bradorego.com/categories/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:26:53 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://bradorego.com/categories/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Static</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Apr 2016 12:26:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/back-to-static/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Static generators (e.g. Hugo) are pretty cool. Ease of use/production directly relates to content creation. It&#39;s okay to borrow aesthetics/technologies/designs from others.   As you might be able to tell, my last blog post is from 2014. It was about time to get back on the blog horse but also give the site a little facelift. I&amp;rsquo;d migrated blog platforms in the past, but never really took the time to think about how my own personal site was hosted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progressive Enhancement with Phonegap</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/progressive-enhancement-with-phonegap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2014 16:46:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/progressive-enhancement-with-phonegap/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Enabling native-level functionality on a hosted web app is really cool. Code reuse is also pretty cool. Beware of the gotchas. There are always gotchas.   Note: This blog post is the long-form answer to this StackOverflow post I made about it (which is, at the time of writing, the #1 Google result for &amp;ldquo;progressive enhancement phonegap&amp;rdquo;). Also worth noting this guide only addresses Android right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Foursquare Heatmap &amp; Remote Sensing</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/foursquare-heatmap--remote-sensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2013 17:21:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/foursquare-heatmap--remote-sensing/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Foursquare&#39;s API and Google Maps are pretty easy to work with. Creating a new product can be as easy as combining two existing technologies. New products create opportunities for new experiences.   A little over a month ago (technically during the Foursquare Hackathon, but I was working from home due to Red Eye) I spent a few hours one weekend hacking together an idea I&amp;rsquo;d come up with when working on Foursquare integration for Trinker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zebradog</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/case-study/zebradog/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2013 15:10:22 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/case-study/zebradog/</guid>
      <description>About Zebradog is an environmental graphic design firm located in Madison, WI who specializes in creating immersive, branded experiences for their clients. Zebradog&amp;rsquo;s multidisciplinary team of architects, graphic designers, and software developers blend the physical and digital realms, creating novel digital applications of technology for interactive multimedia and website design.
Working with Zebradog gave me the opportunity to work with an extremely talented team as well as push the limits of web technology in the interactive multimedia space.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Site!</title>
      <link>http://bradorego.com/new-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Nov 2012 17:32:13 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://bradorego.com/new-site/</guid>
      <description>TL;DNR  Drupal is cool, powerful, mature. Making it easier to create content is important to how likely it is to happen. Keeping up with technology and the design community is important.   It only took me about 10 months, but I&amp;rsquo;ve finally gotten around to rebuilding this site to have a purpose. I originally built a personal website when I was leaving Epic with the intention of having a place to show my past work as well as a place to play around with new technologies on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>