<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on bradorego.com</title>
    <link>https://bradorego.com/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on bradorego.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 16:38:15 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://bradorego.com/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Flow</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/2013-03-the-importance-of-flow</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2013 16:38:15 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/2013-03-the-importance-of-flow</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Pop-ups are distracting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Design your life to have less sudden distractions and you&amp;rsquo;ll be more productive and happier.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Desiging user experiences that encourage flow are good.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve become more and more interested in &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flow_(psychology)&#34;&gt;Flow &lt;/a&gt;recently. As a psych major, flow is something I&amp;rsquo;ve been aware of for a long time, but I always thought of it as something that just happens, and never gave it much thought. It wasn&amp;rsquo;t until an unrelated talk by former psych professor &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.psych.rochester.edu/people/deci_edward/index.html&#34;&gt;Ed Deci&lt;/a&gt; I was listening to a few months ago that got me thinking about flow in the context of UX.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that Prof. Deci said that got me thinking was actually about humanistic psychotherapy. Deci studies motivation, and is co-creator of the esteemed &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.selfdeterminationtheory.org/&#34;&gt;Self-Determination Theory&lt;/a&gt;. What SDT/Deci says is that intrinsic motivation is inherent in people, and it is the product of a situation that features of set of characteristics (autonomy, competence, relatedness). It is also possible (and unfortunately, very common) to thwart these needs, which leads to poor mental health, lack of motivation, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Concidentally, research has shown a fairly high overlap between the conditions for flow and the basis of SDT. Flow requires a level of challenge that is adequately matched to the abilities of the participant (competence), the activity must have clear goals an progress (relatedness - sort of), and the task must present clear, immediate, and constant feedback, so that the participant can adjust performance. &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mihaly_Csikszentmihalyi&#34;&gt;Mihaly Csikszentmihalyi&lt;/a&gt; (&amp;ldquo;cheek-sent-mee-hah-yee&amp;rdquo;), a world leader in flow, published this graph to express the relationship between challenge and skill:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/importance-of-flow/challenge-vs-skill.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are also things that can absolutely ruin flow, which is actually the motivation behind this post. I have a new worst enemy when it comes to reading stories on some popular news sites/blogs, and it&amp;rsquo;s this thing:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/importance-of-flow/comment-box.png&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hate this thing so much. Any time I&amp;rsquo;m reading a news story on TechCrunch, I&amp;rsquo;m usually immersed in the experience and enjoying the read until this little thing pops up in the lower right of my browser window. Its sudden appearance grabs my attention, and I instinctively look at it. After that, I murmur something under my breath and then go ba-&amp;hellip;wait, where was I? What was I just reading?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s not a major disturbance, as I quickly regain my concentration and get back to reading, but with new/popular articles, this happens several times during my read. This little blip in concentration - a break in my flow - slows me down and sullies my experience. This happens to us all the time, what with cell phones buzzing and Facebook notifications popping up and emails rolling in constantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Note-taking</title>
      <link>https://bradorego.com/2013-02-note-taking</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2013 16:22:57 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bradorego.com/2013-02-note-taking</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;tldnr&#34;&gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;TL;DNR&lt;/h4&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Memory is fallible, and humans tend to remember the most intense part and the ending of any experience.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Finding systems that work for you is essential to productivity.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Limit the number of choices a user has to (or has the opportunity to) make. Choose smart defaults and hide most options.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;hr/&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a habit when it comes to books. When I read a book, I almost always underline/take notes in the margin. I started doing so sometime in high school, when Literature teachers started telling us it was okay to write in books. The practice carried me through my studies, and I&amp;rsquo;ve enjoyed it so much it&amp;rsquo;s spilled over into my personal/leisure reading (mind you, all of my leisure reading is non-fiction). You can actually tell which books in my personal collection were books I really enjoyed/valued based on how heavily marked up they are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since graduating from college, I&amp;rsquo;ve started a new version of the practice. Now, after finishing a book (sometimes immediately, but usually after a little time), I go back through the book and look over all of the underlining and notes I took. Generally speaking, when I underline something, it&amp;rsquo;s because it had a certian salience or value to me at the time. So, as I recount these notes, I take a mini post-it note and write whatever value I was trying to glean from it, and then I stick it to the margin of that page. The results look something like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://bradorego.com/img/posts/notetaking/paradox5.jpg&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only does this practice reinforce what I&amp;rsquo;ve learned from that book, but it also changes the way I&amp;rsquo;ve experienced reading that book. In Barry Schwartz&amp;rsquo;s book &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Paradox-Choice-Why-More-Less/dp/0060005696&#34;&gt;The Paradox of Choice&lt;/a&gt;&amp;rdquo;, he cites &lt;a href=&#34;http://profron.net/happiness/files/readings/Kahneman_ObjectiveHappiness.pdf&#34;&gt;a study by Daniel Kahneman&lt;/a&gt;&amp;nbsp;which recounts the way we experience and remember the utility of something (that is, how much we enjoyed it).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What Kahneman et al. found is that our remembered utility is governed by two main factors:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our experience of the peak (or most intense) portion (good/bad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our experience of the ending (good/bad)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can imagine, this has an interesting implication for all parts of life, but particularly, for the design of user interfaces and user experiences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anecdotally, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard people (users) explain their experience with a particular piece of technology. While I don&amp;rsquo;t recall hearing much about the ending (maybe I just don&amp;rsquo;t pay attention), it seems that many users are &amp;ldquo;sold&amp;rdquo; on one particular instance where either a) the system did something cool/fun/awesome (e.g. MailChimp&amp;rsquo;s Freddie the monkey&amp;rsquo;s awesome quotes) or b) the product was particularly handy/useful in a given situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The minor details of the interface, animations, colors, typography, etc. that designers and marketing teams undoubtedly spent hours laboring over have almost no value to users. I&amp;rsquo;m sure they add to the positive experience, and &amp;ldquo;grease the slicks&amp;rdquo; between the user and their end goal, but when we really get down and think about what it is we&amp;rsquo;re designing for, the minor details that can hold projects up (should) melt away. Your perfectly-aligned-and-proportioned interface elements won&amp;rsquo;t matter at all if the user can&amp;rsquo;t do what they want/need to do with your product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schwartz also discusses an incredible array of information and concepts that I believe everyone should be aware of, such as opportunity costs, satisficing vs. maximizing, and the role of utility (esp. diminishing utility) in our daily lives. I&amp;rsquo;d highly recommend giving it a read, as I&amp;rsquo;ve personally seen benefit in my life by putting some of his suggestions into play.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>